<urlset xmlns="http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9" xmlns:video="http://www.google.com/schemas/sitemap-video/1.1"><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/mini-laparoscopic-cholecystectomy-with-intraoperative-cholangiogram-for-systematic-cholelithiasis-gallstones/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/170206-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Mini-Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy with Intraoperative Cholangiogram for Symptomatic Cholelithiasis (Gallstones) - standard</video:title><video:description>Minimal invasive laparoscopic cholecystectomy is the typical surgical treatment for cholelithiasis (gallstones), where patients present with a history of upper abdominal pain and episodes of biliary colic. The classic technique for minimal invasive laparoscopic cholecystectomy involves four ports: one umbilical port, two subcostal ports, and a single epigastric port. The Society of American Gastrointestinal and Endoscopic Surgeons (SAGES) has instituted a six-step strategy to foster a universal culture of safety for cholecystectomy and minimize risk of bile duct injury. The technical steps are documented within the context of the surgical video for (1) achieving a critical view of safety for identification of the cystic duct and artery, (2) intraoperative time-out prior to management of the ductal structures, (3) recognizing the zone of significant risk of injury, and (4) routine intraoperative cholangiography for imaging of the biliary tree. In this case, the patient presented with symptomatic biliary colic due to a gallstone seen on the ultrasound in the gallbladder. The patient was managed with mini-laparoscopic cholecystectomy using 3mm ports for the epigastric and subcostal port sites with intraoperative fluoroscopic cholangiogram. Specifically, the senior author encountered a tight cystic duct preventing the insertion of the cholangiocatheter and the surgical video describes how the author managed the cystic duct for achieving a cholangiogram, in addition to the entire technical details of laparoscopic cholecystectomy. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/v1/uds/pd/4741948344001/201709/1236/4741948344001_5590439645001_5590421405001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1110</video:duration><video:publication_date>2017-09-27</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/170206-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Mini-Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy with Intraoperative Cholangiogram for Symptomatic Cholelithiasis (Gallstones) - extended</video:title><video:description>Minimal invasive laparoscopic cholecystectomy is the typical surgical treatment for cholelithiasis (gallstones), where patients present with a history of upper abdominal pain and episodes of biliary colic. The classic technique for minimal invasive laparoscopic cholecystectomy involves four ports: one umbilical port, two subcostal ports, and a single epigastric port. The Society of American Gastrointestinal and Endoscopic Surgeons (SAGES) has instituted a six-step strategy to foster a universal culture of safety for cholecystectomy and minimize risk of bile duct injury. The technical steps are documented within the context of the surgical video for (1) achieving a critical view of safety for identification of the cystic duct and artery, (2) intraoperative time-out prior to management of the ductal structures, (3) recognizing the zone of significant risk of injury, and (4) routine intraoperative cholangiography for imaging of the biliary tree. In this case, the patient presented with symptomatic biliary colic due to a gallstone seen on the ultrasound in the gallbladder. The patient was managed with mini-laparoscopic cholecystectomy using 3mm ports for the epigastric and subcostal port sites with intraoperative fluoroscopic cholangiogram. Specifically, the senior author encountered a tight cystic duct preventing the insertion of the cholangiocatheter and the surgical video describes how the author managed the cystic duct for achieving a cholangiogram, in addition to the entire technical details of laparoscopic cholecystectomy. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/v1/uds/pd/4741948344001/201709/780/4741948344001_5590445154001_5590434244001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2000</video:duration><video:publication_date>2017-09-27</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/superficial-radial-sensory-nerve-release-with-tenotomy-of-the-brachioradialis-tendon/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/170201-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Radial Sensory Nerve Release with Tenotomy of the Brachioradialis Tendon - standard</video:title><video:description>The superficial radial sensory nerve can be entrapped between the brachioradialis and extensor carpi radialis longus tendons as the radial sensory nerve courses superficially from its deep origin. Compression of the radial sensory nerve presents with numbness and/or pain on the dorsal radial aspect of the hand. Pronation of the hand exacerbates these symptoms as the interval between these two tendons decreases. Decompression of the radial sensory nerve involves a muscle tenotomy of the brachioradialis tendon. The brachioradialis is expendable as the biceps brachii and brachialis provides redundant function for elbow flexion. The lateral antebrachial cutaneous nerve has a superficial course to the radial sensory nerve and the branches of this nerve are protected during decompression. In this case, the patient presented with a radial nerve palsy nine months following a humeral fracture treated with an open reduction and internal fixation. Electrodiagnostic studies revealed fibrillations and motor unit potentials predicting recovery of the radial nerve. A posterior interosseous nerve release was performed and the patient recovered radial motor nerve function thereafter, however the patient continued with complaints of numbness and tingling in the radial sensory nerve territory. Provocative tests were elicited at the radial sensory nerve entrapment point and the patient underwent the decompression of the radial sensory nerve by neurolysis and tenotomy of the brachialis tendon. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5311266841001_5311258863001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>268</video:duration><video:publication_date>2017-02-05</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/170201-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Radial Sensory Nerve Release with Tenotomy of the Brachioradialis Tendon - extended</video:title><video:description>The superficial radial sensory nerve can be entrapped between the brachioradialis and extensor carpi radialis longus tendons as the radial sensory nerve courses superficially from its deep origin. Compression of the radial sensory nerve presents with numbness and/or pain on the dorsal radial aspect of the hand. Pronation of the hand exacerbates these symptoms as the interval between these two tendons decreases. Decompression of the radial sensory nerve involves a muscle tenotomy of the brachioradialis tendon. The brachioradialis is expendable as the biceps brachii and brachialis provides redundant function for elbow flexion. The lateral antebrachial cutaneous nerve has a superficial course to the radial sensory nerve and the branches of this nerve are protected during decompression. In this case, the patient presented with a radial nerve palsy nine months following a humeral fracture treated with an open reduction and internal fixation. Electrodiagnostic studies revealed fibrillations and motor unit potentials predicting recovery of the radial nerve. A posterior interosseous nerve release was performed and the patient recovered radial motor nerve function thereafter, however the patient continued with complaints of numbness and tingling in the radial sensory nerve territory. Provocative tests were elicited at the radial sensory nerve entrapment point and the patient underwent the decompression of the radial sensory nerve by neurolysis and tenotomy of the brachialis tendon. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5311270758001_5311263901001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>462</video:duration><video:publication_date>2017-02-05</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/common-peroneal-nerve-release-at-the-fibular-head/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/161012-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Common Peroneal Nerve Release at the Fibular Head - standard</video:title><video:description>Entrapment of the common peroneal nerve (CPN) at the fibular head is an under-recognized lower extremity neuropathy that contributes to weakness of the musculature within the anterior and lateral compartments of the leg and progress to foot drop. As well, there can be numbness/pain within the territory of the superficial and deep peroneal nerve. Compression of the CPN can be attributed primarily to the posterior crural intermuscular septum found deep to the leading-edge of the peroneus longus. The anterior crural intermuscular septum and a third intermuscular septum are also associated with this compression neuropathy, as well as the surrounding fascia layer that entraps the CPN on top of the deep tendinous fascia. These structures are released to decompress the CPN at the fibular head. Motor branches from the CPN have been seen to pierce these intermuscular septums.  In this case, the patient presented with a complex history of neuropathic pain in the lower left leg following multiple knee surgeries over a span of many years. During examination, the patient was able to tolerate light touch related to compression-type injury rather than withdrawing from severe pain in keeping with a neurectomy-type injury; thus compression neuropathy and not neuroma injury was suspected. The scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride revealed provocation, first at the CPN at the fibular head, then second at the saphenous nerve in the thigh, and then third at the superficial peroneal nerve. Her surgical management included the release of these three nerves. This video outlines the surgical technique for releasing the CPN at the fibular head. The lateral sural cutaneous nerve was not evident in this case. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5196148151001_5196138435001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>445</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-11-04</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/161012-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Common Peroneal Nerve Release at the Fibular Head - extended</video:title><video:description>Entrapment of the common peroneal nerve (CPN) at the fibular head is an under-recognized lower extremity neuropathy that contributes to weakness of the musculature within the anterior and lateral compartments of the leg and progress to foot drop. As well, there can be numbness/pain within the territory of the superficial and deep peroneal nerve. Compression of the CPN can be attributed primarily to the posterior crural intermuscular septum found deep to the leading-edge of the peroneus longus. The anterior crural intermuscular septum and a third intermuscular septum are also associated with this compression neuropathy, as well as the surrounding fascia layer that entraps the CPN on top of the deep tendinous fascia. These structures are released to decompress the CPN at the fibular head. Motor branches from the CPN have been seen to pierce these intermuscular septums.  In this case, the patient presented with a complex history of neuropathic pain in the lower left leg following multiple knee surgeries over a span of many years. During examination, the patient was able to tolerate light touch related to compression-type injury rather than withdrawing from severe pain in keeping with a neurectomy-type injury; thus compression neuropathy and not neuroma injury was suspected. The scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride revealed provocation, first at the CPN at the fibular head, then second at the saphenous nerve in the thigh, and then third at the superficial peroneal nerve. Her surgical management included the release of these three nerves. This video outlines the surgical technique for releasing the CPN at the fibular head. The lateral sural cutaneous nerve was not evident in this case. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5196153673001_5196135909001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>802</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-11-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/superficial-peroneal-nerve-release-in-the-lower-leg/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/150506-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Peroneal Nerve Release in the Lower Leg - standard</video:title><video:description>Compression of the superficial peroneal nerve (SPN) is due to the superficial fascial layer that encapsulates the SPN and its distal entrapment point called the transverse crural ligament. These structures are typically the cause for numbness and pain in the territory of the SPN. Release of the SPN involves the longitudinal release of the superficial fascial layer and the transverse crural ligament. A lateral and anterior fasciotomy is also performed both longitudinally and transversely. Care is taken to look for two branches of the SPN and decompress both branches. This release is performed on patients that present with peroneal neuropathy that fail to resolve from conservative management and have symptoms that localize to the territory of the SPN. In this case, the patient presented with a complex history of neuropathic pain in the lower left leg following multiple knee surgeries over a span of many years. During examination, the patient was able to tolerate light touch related to compression-type injury rather than withdrawing from severe pain in keeping with a neurectomy-type injury; thus compression neuropathy and not neuroma injury was suspected. The scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride revealed provocation, first at the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head, then second at the saphenous nerve in the thigh, and then third at the SPN. Her surgical management included the release of these three nerves. This video outlines the surgical technique for releasing the SPN in the lower leg. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5163152465001_5163129997001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>371</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-10-09</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/150506-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Peroneal Nerve Release in the Lower Leg - extended</video:title><video:description>Compression of the superficial peroneal nerve (SPN) is due to the superficial fascial layer that encapsulates the SPN and its distal entrapment point called the transverse crural ligament. These structures are typically the cause for numbness and pain in the territory of the SPN. Release of the SPN involves the longitudinal release of the superficial fascial layer and the transverse crural ligament. A lateral and anterior fasciotomy is also performed both longitudinally and transversely. Care is taken to look for two branches of the SPN and decompress both branches. This release is performed on patients that present with peroneal neuropathy that fail to resolve from conservative management and have symptoms that localize to the territory of the SPN. In this case, the patient presented with a complex history of neuropathic pain in the lower left leg following multiple knee surgeries over a span of many years. During examination, the patient was able to tolerate light touch related to compression-type injury rather than withdrawing from severe pain in keeping with a neurectomy-type injury; thus compression neuropathy and not neuroma injury was suspected. The scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride revealed provocation, first at the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head, then second at the saphenous nerve in the thigh, and then third at the SPN. Her surgical management included the release of these three nerves. This video outlines the surgical technique for releasing the SPN in the lower leg. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5163151598001_5163143559001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>665</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-10-09</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/revision-ulnar-nerve-transposition-following-failed-submuscular-ulnar-nerve-transposition/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/160708-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Revision Ulnar Nerve Transposition Following Failed Submuscular Ulnar Nerve Transposition - standard</video:title><video:description>Failed surgical management of cubital tunnel syndrome may warrant a revision ulnar nerve transposition. Revision surgery is associated with increased technical difficulty depending on the primary procedure. The senior author's preferred technique for management of cubital tunnel syndrome is a transmuscular ulnar nerve transposition. The technique for revision surgery incorporates methods towards a transmuscular transposition. In this case, a 23-year-old patient presented with a three-year history of significant and continuous ulnar neuropathy two-years following an anterior submuscular ulnar nerve transposition. Examination revealed ulnar intrinsic atrophy and decreased ulnar nerve sensation with normal and intact medial antebrachial cutaneous nerve sensation. Electrodiagnostic studies include small ulnar CMAP amplitude with absent SNAP and fibrillations with motor unit potentials. The scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride hierarchy revealed positive provocations in the order of the cubital tunnel, Guyon's canal, and Struthers' ligament. Surgical management for this case includes revision ulnar nerve transposition, supercharge anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer for motor recovery, side-to-side bridging nerve grafts with acellularized nerve allografts from median to ulnar sensory nerves for early sensory recovery, and a flexor digitorum profundus tenodesis. This video documents the revision transposition component of this patient's surgical management. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5104156098001_5104150350001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1167</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-08-30</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/160708-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Revision Ulnar Nerve Transposition Following Failed Submuscular Ulnar Nerve Transposition - extended</video:title><video:description>Failed surgical management of cubital tunnel syndrome may warrant a revision ulnar nerve transposition. Revision surgery is associated with increased technical difficulty depending on the primary procedure. The senior author's preferred technique for management of cubital tunnel syndrome is a transmuscular ulnar nerve transposition. The technique for revision surgery incorporates methods towards a transmuscular transposition. In this case, a 23-year-old patient presented with a three-year history of significant and continuous ulnar neuropathy two-years following an anterior submuscular ulnar nerve transposition. Examination revealed ulnar intrinsic atrophy and decreased ulnar nerve sensation with normal and intact medial antebrachial cutaneous nerve sensation. Electrodiagnostic studies include small ulnar CMAP amplitude with absent SNAP and fibrillations with motor unit potentials. The scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride hierarchy revealed positive provocations in the order of the cubital tunnel, Guyon's canal, and Struthers' ligament. Surgical management for this case includes revision ulnar nerve transposition, supercharge anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer for motor recovery, side-to-side bridging nerve grafts with acellularized nerve allografts from median to ulnar sensory nerves for early sensory recovery, and a flexor digitorum profundus tenodesis. This video documents the revision transposition component of this patient's surgical management. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5104162194001_5104140733001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2425</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-08-30</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/examination-of-a-patient-with-multiple-nerve-injuries-and-neuropathic-pain-following-a-laceration-at-the-distal-forearm/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/160809-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Examination of a Patient with Multiple Nerve Injuries and Neuropathic Pain Following a Laceration at the Distal Forearm - presentation</video:title><video:description>Examining patients with multiple nerve injuries and neuropathic pain can be difficult due to the number of nerves that have overlapping sensory territories. As well, it is important to distinguish pain from nerve compression (needing just simple decompression) versus pain from a neurotmetic injury (requiring neurectomy with proximal transposition or repair). Through a systematic method of assessment, one can create a management strategy that will help patients understand their injury and propose an operative plan for treating their neuropathic pain. In this case, a 69-year-old patient suffered a deep laceration injury to her distal forearm, which transected several flexor/extensor tendons, "radial sensory" nerve, and 50% of her median nerve. These structures were primarily repaired within hours of her injury and overtime the patient has recovered her median nerve sensation and motor function. However, she presented to our institution two-years following with complaints of significant neuropathic pain with diminishing strength. This examination video is a step-by-step assessment of this patient with neuropathic pain and includes tips for prioritizing and distinguishing the involved sensory territories. This video also discusses an operative plan that includes a staged neurectomy and proximal transpositions of the palmar cutaneous branch of the median nerve (PCM) and lateral antebrachial cutaneous nerve with a radial sensory nerve decompression and brachioradialis tenotomy. - presentation</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5080285449001_5080247565001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>604</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-08-11</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/160809-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Examination of a Patient with Multiple Nerve Injuries and Neuropathic Pain Following a Laceration at the Distal Forearm - exam</video:title><video:description>Examining patients with multiple nerve injuries and neuropathic pain can be difficult due to the number of nerves that have overlapping sensory territories. As well, it is important to distinguish pain from nerve compression (needing just simple decompression) versus pain from a neurotmetic injury (requiring neurectomy with proximal transposition or repair). Through a systematic method of assessment, one can create a management strategy that will help patients understand their injury and propose an operative plan for treating their neuropathic pain. In this case, a 69-year-old patient suffered a deep laceration injury to her distal forearm, which transected several flexor/extensor tendons, "radial sensory" nerve, and 50% of her median nerve. These structures were primarily repaired within hours of her injury and overtime the patient has recovered her median nerve sensation and motor function. However, she presented to our institution two-years following with complaints of significant neuropathic pain with diminishing strength. This examination video is a step-by-step assessment of this patient with neuropathic pain and includes tips for prioritizing and distinguishing the involved sensory territories. This video also discusses an operative plan that includes a staged neurectomy and proximal transpositions of the palmar cutaneous branch of the median nerve (PCM) and lateral antebrachial cutaneous nerve with a radial sensory nerve decompression and brachioradialis tenotomy. - exam</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_5081292058001_5081251773001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1235</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-08-12</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/carpal-tunnel-syndrome/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160510-4A-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</video:title><video:description>This presentation discusses carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS) and median neuropathy in the context of compression neuropathies. In particular, this presentation details the specific nuances for (1) an open carpal tunnel release, (2) revision carpal tunnel surgery, and (3) decompression of the median nerve in the forearm. Patients that fail the primary carpal tunnel release and require secondary surgery, present with either persistent, recurrent, or new symptoms. This classification for revision surgery is discussed to indicate the nature of the patient’s problem and define the appropriate management. Additionally, the technical nuances for decompression of the median nerve in the forearm are presented.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4890578014001_4890528002001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1030</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-12</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/cubital-tunnel-syndrome/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160510-3-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Cubital Tunnel Syndrome</video:title><video:description>This presentation discusses cubital tunnel syndrome (CTS) and ulnar neuropathy in the context of compression neuropathies. In particular, this presentation details several topics that includes (1) controversy of management for CTS, (2) patient evaluation, (3) surgical management, (4) post-operative management, and (5) an in-depth review of the surgical procedures involved for management. Additionally, revision ulnar nerve surgery is discussed from the senior author's experience with the appropriate management.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4890587489001_4890527996001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2225</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-12</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/thoracic-outlet-syndrome/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160510-2-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Thoracic Outlet Syndrome</video:title><video:description>This presentation discusses thoracic outlet syndrome (TOS) in the context of compression neuropathies. In particular, this presentation details conservation management of TOS and the pathogenesis of cumulative trauma disorder. Additionally, a case presentation for conservative management is included. When conservative management fails, our surgical management is a thoracic outlet decompression through a scalenectomy of the anterior and middle scalenes. A step-by-step illustrated and technical approach of this procedure is included.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4890539663001_4890511727001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>786</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-12</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/introduction-to-compression-neuropathy/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160510-1-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Introduction to Compression Neuropathy</video:title><video:description>This presentation is an introduction to compression neuropathies and examines the histological premise for nerve compression with methodology for evaluating these patients. Knowledge of compression neuropathy is key for treating patients with nerve injuries and serves as a foundation for building further expertise within the specialty of nerve surgery. This presentation includes a discussion surrounding the histopathology of nerve compression and its progression over time. Double crush syndrome is also included in this discussion. The second component of this presentation includes methodology for evaluation patients with nerve compression. This details the patient work-up, provocative tests and maneuvers, scratch collapse test, and strategies for sensory examination.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4890591568001_4890517971001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1637</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-12</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/strategies-of-peripheral-nerve-surgery/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160509-Thumbnail-Presentation.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Strategies of Peripheral Nerve Surgery</video:title><video:description>This presentation is one of our principle lectures that discusses strategies for managing nerve injuries with gaps. These strategies include nerve repair, grafting, allografts, conduits, acellularized allografts, and nerve transfers. An understanding of these strategies is important for the framework of nerve reconstruction and the possible options that can be provided to patients with nerve injuries. Each strategy is discussed with their advantages and disadvantages in relation to other strategies.  </video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4886001688001_4885921517001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>3180</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-09</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/sensory-nerve-transfers-for-hand-function/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160508-5-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Sensory Nerve Transfers for Hand Function</video:title><video:description>While not as popular as motor nerve transfers, sensory nerve transfers are an important component of the reconstructive algorithm for restoring sensation and/or managing pain. The type of sensory nerve transfer performed depends on whether the targeted sensory distribution is a critical or non-critical territory to reconstruct. End-to-end transfers are for critical sensation and end-to-side transfers are for non-critical sensations. This presentation demonstrates the sensory nerve transfers for restoring radial, median and ulnar nerve function and should be coupled with the associated motor reconstruction. Experimental research is also presented to warrant end-to-side nerve transfers.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4885825497001_4885789077001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1781</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-09</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/nerve-transfers-for-ulnar-nerve-injuries/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160508-4A-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Nerve Transfers for Ulnar Nerve Injuries</video:title><video:description>In this presentation, we discuss nerve transfers and reconstructive strategies for managing ulnar nerve injuries. The anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer is the procedure, where we utilize end-to-end repair for complete nerve injuries and end-to-side repair for incomplete or recovering nerve injuries. This presentation documents the indications and technical aspects for these procedures with the accompanying sensory reconstruction strategies.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4885804549001_4885741673001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1136</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-09</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/nerve-transfers-for-median-nerve-injuries/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160508-3-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Nerve Transfers for Median Nerve Injuries</video:title><video:description>This presentation details reconstructive options for median nerve injuries, specifically nerve transfers to reinnervate the pronator teres and anterior interosseous nerve. These two recipient nerves are critical for median nerve function and strategies for reinnervation depend on the availability of donor nerves following injury. Patient outcomes are also presented following technical discussion.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4885803211001_4885751970001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1280</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-09</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/nerve-transfers-for-radial-nerve-injuries/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160508-2-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Nerve Transfers for Radial Nerve Injuries</video:title><video:description>This presentation details reconstructive options for radial nerve injuries, specifically median to radial nerve transfers. Indications and discussion surrounding the advantages and disadvantages for nerve transfers versus tendon transfers are presented, however the goals and expectations of patients will help outline the appropriate surgical management. A step-by-step walkthrough is discussed for this nerve transfer, in addition to how the procedure is modified to incorporate a pronator teres to ECRB tendon transfer. Following the surgical technique, the rehabilitation protocol is outlined and examples of long-term patient outcomes are presented.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4885778722001_4885739133001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1184</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-09</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/introduction-and-indications-for-nerve-transfers/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160508-1-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Introduction and Indications for Nerve Transfers</video:title><video:description>This presentation is an introduction to nerve transfers and details the indications for performing these procedures. Experimental studies are discussed in respect to nerve injury and recovery and the window for reinnervation. The classification for nerve injuries is also reviewed with an additional category that distinguishes recovery to either favorable (I, II, III degree) or unfavorable (IV, V degree). Nerve transfers are performed for unfavorable nerve injuries and the associated indications are provided within this presentation. Factors for poor functional recovery are also discussed to optimize outcomes following nerve transfers.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4885749996001_4885739061001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>789</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-09</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/nerve-transfers-for-shoulder-and-elbow-function/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160507-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Nerve Transfers for Shoulder and Elbow Function</video:title><video:description>TThis presentation is a comprehensive review of our strategies for restoring function to the shoulder and elbow through nerve transfers. In particular, these transfers are discussed in reference to brachial plexus injuries with an approach at an individual nerve-level. Technical approaches are offered for each nerve transfer to restore shoulder and elbow function. This is our third revision to this topic.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4883380057001_4883338187001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>3514</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-07</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/brachial-plexus-reconstruction/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160504-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Brachial Plexus Reconstruction</video:title><video:description>This presentation describes our approach to management of brachial plexus injuries. This includes a description of the nerve injury classification and the appropriate electrodiagnostic tools used for assessing these challenging cases. Additionally, case examples are presented to review how to examine and diagnosis these patients. Surgical management strategies are also presented for root injuries through various combinations of nerve transfers. Finally, exposure of the brachial plexus is discussed through either a supraclavicular approach or infraclavicular approach.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4878325060001_4878235103001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2779</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/surgeon-as-a-perpetual-learner-nerve-cases-i-have-learned-most-from/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/160214-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Surgeon as a Perpetual Learner: Nerve Cases I Have Learned Most From</video:title><video:description>This presentation was given at the 2016 American Society for Peripheral Nerve as part of a panel describing the experiences and cases that the panelists learned the most from. In this presentation, the primary author describes her experiences with the pain evaluation as one of the most essential tools for diagnoses patients with nerve injuries. Additional discussion on dealing with difficult patients and the utility of the scratch collapse test are included. Finally, the primary author discusses her experience with the controversy surrounding cumulative trauma disorder and the movement towards a new term called posture-related upper extremity pain (PRUEP).</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4873792247001_4873717595001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1478</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-02</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/tracheal-resection-stomal-stricture-tracheostomy/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/151027-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Tracheal Resection of a Stomal Stricture and Repair Following a Tracheostomy - standard</video:title><video:description>Tracheotomy and endotracheal intubation continues to be most common cause for tracheal stenosis and management involves tracheal resection and reapproximation. In this case, the patient presented with a history of multiple cardiac surgical procedures. She undergone a tracheostomy and developed recent symptoms of stridor. Imaging studies demonstrated a typical tracheostomy and stromal stricture. Surgical management involved tracheal resection and primary anastomosis. This video details the specifics for a tracheal resection from incision to closure. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804382949001_4777256066001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>843</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-27</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/151027-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Tracheal Resection of a Stomal Stricture and Repair Following a Tracheostomy - extended</video:title><video:description>Tracheotomy and endotracheal intubation continues to be most common cause for tracheal stenosis and management involves tracheal resection and reapproximation. In this case, the patient presented with a history of multiple cardiac surgical procedures. She undergone a tracheostomy and developed recent symptoms of stridor. Imaging studies demonstrated a typical tracheostomy and stromal stricture. Surgical management involved tracheal resection and primary anastomosis. This video details the specifics for a tracheal resection from incision to closure. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804392864001_4777247332001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1631</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-27</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/saphenous-nerve-release/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/150403-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Saphenous Nerve Release - standard</video:title><video:description>Entrapment of the saphenous nerve is probably under-recognized and presents with numbness/pain in the infrapatellar region and the medial aspect of the lower leg. The vastoadductor intermuscular septum is responsible for entrapment symptoms as it forms the anterior fascia of the adductor canal, deep to the sartorius muscle. The femoral vessels and saphenous nerve have a course within this canal and the nerve may anteriorly pierce through the intermuscular septum. Decompression of the saphenous nerve involves the release of the vastoadductor intermuscular septum. In this case, the patient presented with severe pain in the lower extremity and diagnosed with complex regional pain syndrome. Her neuropathic pain began seven-years-ago following a revision knee operation for knee stiffness. The patient described the regions of neuropathic pain on the lateral aspect of the foot, lateral aspect of the lower leg, and medial aspect of the thigh. Provocative tests, specifically the scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride, identified provocation in the following order: superficial peroneal nerve, common peroneal nerve, and saphenous nerve. Release of the superficial peroneal nerve, common peroneal nerve, and saphenous nerve were elected. This video details the specifics for the saphenous nerve release. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804383033001_4777212486001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>606</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-27</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/150403-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Saphenous Nerve Release - extended</video:title><video:description>Entrapment of the saphenous nerve is probably under-recognized and presents with numbness/pain in the infrapatellar region and the medial aspect of the lower leg. The vastoadductor intermuscular septum is responsible for entrapment symptoms as it forms the anterior fascia of the adductor canal, deep to the sartorius muscle. The femoral vessels and saphenous nerve have a course within this canal and the nerve may anteriorly pierce through the intermuscular septum. Decompression of the saphenous nerve involves the release of the vastoadductor intermuscular septum. In this case, the patient presented with severe pain in the lower extremity and diagnosed with complex regional pain syndrome. Her neuropathic pain began seven-years-ago following a revision knee operation for knee stiffness. The patient described the regions of neuropathic pain on the lateral aspect of the foot, lateral aspect of the lower leg, and medial aspect of the thigh. Provocative tests, specifically the scratch collapse test with ethyl chloride, identified provocation in the following order: superficial peroneal nerve, common peroneal nerve, and saphenous nerve. Release of the superficial peroneal nerve, common peroneal nerve, and saphenous nerve were elected. This video details the specifics for the saphenous nerve release. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804385561001_4777212490001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1190</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-27</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/medial-triceps-anterior-branch-axillary-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/150302-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Triceps to Anterior Branch of Axillary Nerve Transfer: A Case of Specific Reinnervation - standard</video:title><video:description>The axillary nerve has several distal branches that provide shoulder function through the innervation of the anterior, middle, and posterior deltoid and teres minor, as well as sensation to the lateral arm. Injury to the axillary nerve has been traditionally viewed as either a complete non-favorable injury where recovery does not occur or a favorable injury where recovery does occur. However, there are situations of mixed injuries where both these scenarios are true, and the axillary nerve has components that will and will not recovery. This mixed nerve injury can be confirmed with the use of electrodiagnostic studies. Management of these cases is to reinnervate the non-recovering components, while protecting the recovering components. The medial triceps branch is an available donor for reconstruction. In this case, the patient suffered an upper brachial plexus injury following a severe fall and lost shoulder function. Electromyography at three months post-injury reported motor unit potentials in the middle and posterior deltoid to recovery, however the anterior deltoid did not have motor unit potentials. Specific reinnervation of the anterior branch of the axillary nerve using the medial triceps branch nerve transfer was elected. This video details the specifics of this nerve transfer. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804389650001_4777194029001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1117</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-27</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/150302-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Triceps to Anterior Branch of Axillary Nerve Transfer: A Case of Specific Reinnervation - extended</video:title><video:description>The axillary nerve has several distal branches that provide shoulder function through the innervation of the anterior, middle, and posterior deltoid and teres minor, as well as sensation to the lateral arm. Injury to the axillary nerve has been traditionally viewed as either a complete non-favorable injury where recovery does not occur or a favorable injury where recovery does occur. However, there are situations of mixed injuries where both these scenarios are true, and the axillary nerve has components that will and will not recovery. This mixed nerve injury can be confirmed with the use of electrodiagnostic studies. Management of these cases is to reinnervate the non-recovering components, while protecting the recovering components. The medial triceps branch is an available donor for reconstruction. In this case, the patient suffered an upper brachial plexus injury following a severe fall and lost shoulder function. Electromyography at three months post-injury reported motor unit potentials in the middle and posterior deltoid to recovery, however the anterior deltoid did not have motor unit potentials. Specific reinnervation of the anterior branch of the axillary nerve using the medial triceps branch nerve transfer was elected. This video details the specifics of this nerve transfer. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804401777001_4775779248001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2510</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-26</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/medial-triceps-to-axillary-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/150105-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Triceps to Axillary Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>Injury to the axillary nerve results in the loss of shoulder function, specifically deltoid and teres minor deficits. This injury can either be isolated or more commonly associated with an upper brachial plexus injury that includes the C5,6 roots. The medial triceps is an available donor for nerve transfer into the axillary nerve and is one part of the double shoulder nerve transfers for shoulder reconstruction following nerve injury. Nerve transfers for the axillary nerve includes reinnervating the deltoid, teres minor, and superior lateral cutaneous nerve territory. In this case, the patient presented six months following a right pan brachial plexus injury with complete C5,6 injury and scapular fracture after a severe ATV accident. While some recovery occurred in the middle/lower plexus, electrodiagnostic studies confirmed no recovery to elbow flexion, deltoid and supra/infraspinatus muscles. The triceps were recovering and thus a medial triceps to axillary nerve transfer was elected with the spinal accessory to suprascapular nerve transfer for shoulder reconstruction. A superior lateral cutaneous end-to-side to radial sensory nerve transfer was also performed for sensation. This video details a reconstruction strategy for the axillary nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804408663001_4791912447001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1077</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/150105-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Triceps to Axillary Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>Injury to the axillary nerve results in the loss of shoulder function, specifically deltoid and teres minor deficits. This injury can either be isolated or more commonly associated with an upper brachial plexus injury that includes the C5,6 roots. The medial triceps is an available donor for nerve transfer into the axillary nerve and is one part of the double shoulder nerve transfers for shoulder reconstruction following nerve injury. Nerve transfers for the axillary nerve includes reinnervating the deltoid, teres minor, and superior lateral cutaneous nerve territory. In this case, the patient presented six months following a right pan brachial plexus injury with complete C5,6 injury and scapular fracture after a severe ATV accident. While some recovery occurred in the middle/lower plexus, electrodiagnostic studies confirmed no recovery to elbow flexion, deltoid and supra/infraspinatus muscles. The triceps were recovering and thus a medial triceps to axillary nerve transfer was elected with the spinal accessory to suprascapular nerve transfer for shoulder reconstruction. A superior lateral cutaneous end-to-side to radial sensory nerve transfer was also performed for sensation. This video details a reconstruction strategy for the axillary nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804420790001_4791946185001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2278</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/supercharge-end-to-side-nerve-transfers/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/141121-Thumbnail-Presentation.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Supercharge End-to-side Nerve Transfers</video:title><video:description>This presentation describes the premise for the supercharge end-to-side nerve transfer and its clinical utility for incomplete injuries involving the ulnar nerve. Specifically, this presentation discuss the indications for this procedures, the research involved for its development, and the technical nuisances of the anterior interosseous to ulnar motor supercharge end-to-side nerve transfer.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4873793214001_4873708713001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1591</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-02</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/brachialis-anterior-interosseous-nerve-transfer-extended-forearm-incision/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140314-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Brachialis to Anterior Interosseous Nerve Transfer with Extended Forearm Incision - standard</video:title><video:description>Loss of flexor pollicis longus and radial profundus function results in a deficit of pinch and reduced grip strength in the hand. This palsy can be isolated or commonly included in a lower brachial plexus injury. The brachialis nerve is an available, synergistic, and powerful donor for transfer in these scenarios, especially in C7,8,T1 injuries and when other common donors are unavailable due to injury like the extensor carpi radialis brevis. In this case, the patient presented three months following a partial C7 and C8,T1 brachial plexus injury from a fall with no recovery on electrodiagnostic studies. The brachialis to anterior interosseous nerve transfer was elected with the supinator to flexor digitorum superficialis nerve transfer and lateral antebrachial cutaneous to ulnar sensory nerve transfer. This video details the specifics for the brachialis transfer with an extended incision into the forearm to confirm the proximal topography of the anterior interosseous fascicle in the median nerve. Additionally, this patient has an anomalous sensory nerve anastomosis from a brachialis nerve branch to the sensory component of the median nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804409955001_4791946190001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1215</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140314-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Brachialis to Anterior Interosseous Nerve Transfer with Extended Forearm Incision - extended</video:title><video:description>Loss of flexor pollicis longus and radial profundus function results in a deficit of pinch and reduced grip strength in the hand. This palsy can be isolated or commonly included in a lower brachial plexus injury. The brachialis nerve is an available, synergistic, and powerful donor for transfer in these scenarios, especially in C7,8,T1 injuries and when other common donors are unavailable due to injury like the extensor carpi radialis brevis. In this case, the patient presented three months following a partial C7 and C8,T1 brachial plexus injury from a fall with no recovery on electrodiagnostic studies. The brachialis to anterior interosseous nerve transfer was elected with the supinator to flexor digitorum superficialis nerve transfer and lateral antebrachial cutaneous to ulnar sensory nerve transfer. This video details the specifics for the brachialis transfer with an extended incision into the forearm to confirm the proximal topography of the anterior interosseous fascicle in the median nerve. Additionally, this patient has an anomalous sensory nerve anastomosis from a brachialis nerve branch to the sensory component of the median nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804423746001_4792039983001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2854</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/median-fcrfds-radial-pinecrb-nerve-transfers-with-pt-to-ecrb-tendon-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140820-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median (FCR/FDS) to Radial (PIN/ECRB) Nerve Transfers with PT to ECRB Tendon Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>Radial nerve palsy is a debilitating nerve injury that results in lost of wrist and finger extension, which classically presents as wrist drop. The two reconstructive options for managing this injury are tendon transfers and nerve transfers, each with their advantages and disadvantages. Nerve transfers are able to provide independent finger extension, however there is an associated prolonged recovery period in comparison to tendon transfers for radial nerve palsy. Electing the appropriate surgical management depends on the patient's demands and needs. Nerve transfers for radial nerve palsy includes two transfers: (1) FCR to PIN and (2) FDS to ECRB. The tendon transfer for wrist extension can be elected for an early outcome and includes the transfer of the pronator teres to ECRB tendon. In this case, the patient presented three months following a severe MVC and suffered a radial nerve transection associated with a humeral facture. Due to the patient's needs, the median to radial nerve transfers were elected with the pronator teres to ECRB tendon transfer. To restore radial nerve sensation, an end-to-side nerve transfer was additionally performed and included the radial sensory nerve end-to-side into the sensory component of the median nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804429729001_4795849330001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1092</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-10</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140820-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median (FCR/FDS) to Radial (PIN/ECRB) Nerve Transfers with PT to ECRB Tendon Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>Radial nerve palsy is a debilitating nerve injury that results in lost of wrist and finger extension, which classically presents as wrist drop. The two reconstructive options for managing this injury are tendon transfers and nerve transfers, each with their advantages and disadvantages. Nerve transfers are able to provide independent finger extension, however there is an associated prolonged recovery period in comparison to tendon transfers for radial nerve palsy. Electing the appropriate surgical management depends on the patient's demands and needs. Nerve transfers for radial nerve palsy includes two transfers: (1) FCR to PIN and (2) FDS to ECRB. The tendon transfer for wrist extension can be elected for an early outcome and includes the transfer of the pronator teres to ECRB tendon. In this case, the patient presented three months following a severe MVC and suffered a radial nerve transection associated with a humeral facture. Due to the patient's needs, the median to radial nerve transfers were elected with the pronator teres to ECRB tendon transfer. To restore radial nerve sensation, an end-to-side nerve transfer was additionally performed and included the radial sensory nerve end-to-side into the sensory component of the median nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804438951001_4795950588001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2373</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-10</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/median-to-radial-nerve-transfers/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/140831-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median to Radial Nerve Transfers</video:title><video:description>This presentation is a description on the median to radial nerve transfers for management of radial nerve palsies. It was presented at the 2014 ASSH Post-Course on distal nerve transfers for brachial plexus injuries. Specifically, this presentation discusses the technical nuisances of this procedure, which can be used as a companion to the surgical tutorial video.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4872514277001_4872506046001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>982</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-01</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/stage-1-cross-facial-nerve-grafting-for-smile/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140520-2-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Stage 1 &#8211; Cross-Facial Nerve Grafting for Smile - standard</video:title><video:description>Facial paralysis causes significant morbidity and dynamic reconstruction aims to address functional, aesthetic, and psychological aspects of the impairment. Cross-facial nerve grafting is a reconstructive strategy used to restore smile function and eye closure in both acute and chronic unilateral injury. In an acute injury, nerve grafting provides regenerating fibers from the donor nerve on the normal side to reinnervate across the face to the similar recipient nerve on the paralyzed side. In a chronic injury where the paralyzed muscle can no longer be reinnervated, the cross-facial nerve graft serves as the first stage to a segmental free functional muscle transfer to reconstruct smile. In this case, the patient presented 4-years-ago with a posterior fossa medulloblastoma, which was removed, and underwent a successful course of chemotherapy. However, the tumor involved partial CN12 and complete CN6 and CN7 nerve paralysis on the left side. Reconstruction included a 2-stage segmental gracilis muscle transfer to reconstruct smile with stage one providing the donor nerve source for the muscle. This video details the selection of the donor buccal branch of the contralateral facial nerve and coaptation of the sural nerve graft as the cross-facial nerve graft. The specifics of the sural nerve harvest are not included in this video. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4931820574001_4795615936001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>607</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-10</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140520-2-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Stage 1 &#8211; Cross-Facial Nerve Grafting for Smile - extended</video:title><video:description>Facial paralysis causes significant morbidity and dynamic reconstruction aims to address functional, aesthetic, and psychological aspects of the impairment. Cross-facial nerve grafting is a reconstructive strategy used to restore smile function and eye closure in both acute and chronic unilateral injury. In an acute injury, nerve grafting provides regenerating fibers from the donor nerve on the normal side to reinnervate across the face to the similar recipient nerve on the paralyzed side. In a chronic injury where the paralyzed muscle can no longer be reinnervated, the cross-facial nerve graft serves as the first stage to a segmental free functional muscle transfer to reconstruct smile. In this case, the patient presented 4-years-ago with a posterior fossa medulloblastoma, which was removed, and underwent a successful course of chemotherapy. However, the tumor involved partial CN12 and complete CN6 and CN7 nerve paralysis on the left side. Reconstruction included a 2-stage segmental gracilis muscle transfer to reconstruct smile with stage one providing the donor nerve source for the muscle. This video details the selection of the donor buccal branch of the contralateral facial nerve and coaptation of the sural nerve graft as the cross-facial nerve graft. The specifics of the sural nerve harvest are not included in this video. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4931831627001_4795694691001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1750</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-10</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/segmental-gracilis-muscle-transfer-mobius-syndrome/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140520-1-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Segmental Gracilis Muscle Transfer for Smile in a Case of Möbius Syndrome - standard</video:title><video:description>Facial paralysis causes significant morbidity and dynamic reconstruction aims to address functional, aesthetic, and psychological aspects of the impairment. Segmental gracilis muscle transfer is a reconstructive strategy used to restore smile function in a chronic injury, where nerve grafting or nerve transfers are no longer an option due to prolonged muscle atrophy or congenital causes. In this case, the patient presented with a congenital neurological disorder called Möbius syndrome, which involved complete bilateral paralysis of CN6, CN7 and partial paralysis of CN12. The patient's inability to smile was due to the absence of facial muscles. A bilateral segmental muscle transfer was elected to reconstruct smile using the gracilis muscle with neurotization with the masseteric nerve. Often, patients with Möbius syndrome do not have a facial vein, as in this patient, and the transverse facial vein and the facial artery were utilized for vascular anastomosis. This video portrays the approach and technical details for performing a segmental gracilis muscle transfer using the donor masseteric nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4931825656001_4796029636001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1590</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-10</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140520-1-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Segmental Gracilis Muscle Transfer for Smile in a Case of Möbius Syndrome - extended</video:title><video:description>Facial paralysis causes significant morbidity and dynamic reconstruction aims to address functional, aesthetic, and psychological aspects of the impairment. Segmental gracilis muscle transfer is a reconstructive strategy used to restore smile function in a chronic injury, where nerve grafting or nerve transfers are no longer an option due to prolonged muscle atrophy or congenital causes. In this case, the patient presented with a congenital neurological disorder called Möbius syndrome, which involved complete bilateral paralysis of CN6, CN7 and partial paralysis of CN12. The patient's inability to smile was due to the absence of facial muscles. A bilateral segmental muscle transfer was elected to reconstruct smile using the gracilis muscle with neurotization with the masseteric nerve. Often, patients with Möbius syndrome do not have a facial vein, as in this patient, and the transverse facial vein and the facial artery were utilized for vascular anastomosis. This video portrays the approach and technical details for performing a segmental gracilis muscle transfer using the donor masseteric nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4931841988001_4796035984001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>3226</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-10</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/jumping-the-nerve-gap/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/140727-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Jumping the Nerve Gap</video:title><video:description>This presentation is part of the upcoming second edition surgical book called Flaps and Reconstructive Surgery by Wei and Mardini. Specifically, this presentation discusses current methods for reconstructing a nerve gap with either a conduit, acellularized nerve allograft, nerve allograft, or nerve autograft. Information on their appropriate use is provided.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4872449975001_4872425052001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1184</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-04-30</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/posterior-approach-spinal-accessory-suprascapular-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140422-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Posterior Approach &#8211; Spinal Accessory to Suprascapular Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>Reconstructing shoulder function following a nerve injury is a challenge due to its dynamic movement originating from several muscles. The supra/infraspinatus muscles are critical for shoulder function in that they initiate abduction of the arm, external rotation, and stabilization of the shoulder joint. In upper brachial plexus injuries, it is common to find a deficit in the suprascapular nerve associated with the axillary and musculocutaneous nerves due to their C5,6 root origins. These patients present with no shoulder function or elbow flexion. Reconstruction includes nerve transfers to innervate the axillary and suprascapular nerves for shoulder function. An available donor nerve for restoring the suprascapular nerve includes the spinal accessory nerve from a posterior or anterior approach. The posterior approach utilizes the distal branches of the accessory nerve that innervates the inferior segments of the trapezius. This video portrays that posterior approach. In this case, a 49-year-old male presented post-Schwannoma resection from the upper brachial plexus with a shoulder and elbow flexion deficit. To reconstruct shoulder function, a spinal accessory to suprascapular nerve transfer was elected with a medial triceps to axillary nerve transfer. To reconstruct elbow flexion, a double fascicular nerve transfer was elected. This video details the posterior approach to reconstructing the suprascapular nerve using the spinal accessory nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804405767001_4791945349001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>806</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140422-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Posterior Approach &#8211; Spinal Accessory to Suprascapular Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>Reconstructing shoulder function following a nerve injury is a challenge due to its dynamic movement originating from several muscles. The supra/infraspinatus muscles are critical for shoulder function in that they initiate abduction of the arm, external rotation, and stabilization of the shoulder joint. In upper brachial plexus injuries, it is common to find a deficit in the suprascapular nerve associated with the axillary and musculocutaneous nerves due to their C5,6 root origins. These patients present with no shoulder function or elbow flexion. Reconstruction includes nerve transfers to innervate the axillary and suprascapular nerves for shoulder function. An available donor nerve for restoring the suprascapular nerve includes the spinal accessory nerve from a posterior or anterior approach. The posterior approach utilizes the distal branches of the accessory nerve that innervates the inferior segments of the trapezius. This video portrays that posterior approach. In this case, a 49-year-old male presented post-Schwannoma resection from the upper brachial plexus with a shoulder and elbow flexion deficit. To reconstruct shoulder function, a spinal accessory to suprascapular nerve transfer was elected with a medial triceps to axillary nerve transfer. To reconstruct elbow flexion, a double fascicular nerve transfer was elected. This video details the posterior approach to reconstructing the suprascapular nerve using the spinal accessory nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804414391001_4791945377001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1619</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/2014-crn-nerve-transfers-for-the-hand/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/140505-3-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2014 CRN – Nerve Transfers for the Hand</video:title><video:description>This presentation is part of the 2014 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures and the second part of the Acute Nerve Injury and Repair lecture. Specifically, this presentation discusses nerve transfers for the hand. This includes motor reconstructive options for radial nerve, median nerve, and ulnar nerve deficits. Additionally, sensory nerve transfers are discussed for these deficits.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4872712288001_4872657270001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>5334</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-01</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/2014-crn-peripheral-nerve-surgery/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/140505-4-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2014 CRN – Peripheral Nerve Surgery</video:title><video:description>This presentation is part of the 2014 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures and the first part of the Acute Nerve Injury and Repair lecture. Specifically, this presentation discusses reconstructive options for nerve injury, which includes nerve repair, nerve grafting, nerve allografts, conduits and acelluarized allografts, and the basis for nerve transfers.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4872755467001_4872722214001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>4428</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-01</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/2014-crn-nerve-transfers-for-the-shoulder-and-elbow/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/140505-2-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2014 CRN – Nerve Transfers for the Shoulder and Elbow</video:title><video:description>This presentation is part of the 2014 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures and the second part of the Brachial Plexus Lesion lecture. Specifically, this presentation discusses nerve transfers for the shoulder and elbow. This includes motor reconstructive options for spinal accessory nerve, suprascapular nerve, axillary nerve, and long thoracic nerve deficits for the shoulder and musculocutaneous nerve and triceps brachii nerve deficits for the elbow.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4872606656001_4872529125001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>3123</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-01</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/2014-crn-brachial-plexus-lesions/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/140505-1-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2014 CRN – Brachial Plexus Lesions</video:title><video:description>This presentation is part of the 2014 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures and the first part of the Brachial Plexus Lesion lecture. Specifically, this presentation discusses the topic of treatment for brachial plexus injuries, which includes presentation of common injury patterns, management algorithms for nerve injuries, and pre-operative and post-operative therapy. Reconstructive options for common brachial plexus injuries are also discussed, however details on these reconstructive options are included in the second part of this lecture (Nerve Transfers for the Shoulder and Elbow).</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4872661654001_4872630885001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2497</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-01</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/radial-nerve-release-at-the-spiral-groove/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/140207-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Radial Nerve Release at the Spiral Groove - standard</video:title><video:description>Radial nerve compression at the level of the humerus is uncommon and occurs at the spiral groove. The radial nerve has an anatomical course proximal below the lateral intermuscular septum and continues distal between the brachialis and brachioradialis muscles. The entrapment point involves the tendinous lateral intermuscular septum and provocative tests will be positive at this. This is a location that is prone to radial nerve injury during humeral factures. Release of the radial nerve at this level involves dividing the lateral intermuscular septum, while protecting the posterior brachial and antebrachial cutaneous nerves that have an adjacent course to the radial nerve proper. The surgical approach involves dissecting the interval between the brachialis and brachioradialis to identify the radial nerve. In this case, the patient presented with pain originating from the neck that radiated along the course of the posterior division and radial nerve. Her C-spine surgery failed and was referred to our institution. Positive provocative tests included the neck, spiral groove, arcade of Frohse, and radial sensory nerve entrapment. The hierarchical scratch collapse test was used. Radial nerve releases were elected at three sites of entrapment in the upper extremity. This video details the release at the spiral groove. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804401834001_4791932094001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>519</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/140207-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Radial Nerve Release at the Spiral Groove - extended</video:title><video:description>Radial nerve compression at the level of the humerus is uncommon and occurs at the spiral groove. The radial nerve has an anatomical course proximal below the lateral intermuscular septum and continues distal between the brachialis and brachioradialis muscles. The entrapment point involves the tendinous lateral intermuscular septum and provocative tests will be positive at this. This is a location that is prone to radial nerve injury during humeral factures. Release of the radial nerve at this level involves dividing the lateral intermuscular septum, while protecting the posterior brachial and antebrachial cutaneous nerves that have an adjacent course to the radial nerve proper. The surgical approach involves dissecting the interval between the brachialis and brachioradialis to identify the radial nerve. In this case, the patient presented with pain originating from the neck that radiated along the course of the posterior division and radial nerve. Her C-spine surgery failed and was referred to our institution. Positive provocative tests included the neck, spiral groove, arcade of Frohse, and radial sensory nerve entrapment. The hierarchical scratch collapse test was used. Radial nerve releases were elected at three sites of entrapment in the upper extremity. This video details the release at the spiral groove. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804406500001_4791945325001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>970</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/superficial-peroneal-and-sural-neuroma-transposition/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140220-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Peroneal and Sural Neuroma Transposition in a Case of Neuropathic Pain Following Foot Surgery - standard</video:title><video:description>Pain resulting from nerve injury can originate from the site of injury (local neuroma pain) and from the collateral sprouting of adjacent sensory territories into the deinnervated territory (hyperalgesic pain). Surgical management of neuropathic pain is controversial and typical management of neuroma pain includes excision and transposition. In our institution, management includes a proximal crush injury to facilitate an axonal injury and a period of prolonged regeneration, neuroma resection with distal end cautery cap, and proximal intermuscular transposition. In the case, the patient presented with severe neuropathic pain in the anterior/lateral region of the ankle and foot, following surgery to correct flat foot deformity. Two attempts to surgically resolve the neuropathic pain from a sural neuroma failed before being referred to our institution. Examination and provocative tests revealed involvement of the sural nerve and superficial peroneal nerve. Surgical management included exploration and transposition of the sural nerve and superficial peroneal nerve with releases of the peroneal nerve at the fibular head, lateral sural nerve, and deep peroneal nerve. The nerves releases were included due to having positive provocative tests during examination. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804408642001_4791907147001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1106</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/140220-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Peroneal and Sural Neuroma Transposition in a Case of Neuropathic Pain Following Foot Surgery - extended</video:title><video:description>Pain resulting from nerve injury can originate from the site of injury (local neuroma pain) and from the collateral sprouting of adjacent sensory territories into the deinnervated territory (hyperalgesic pain). Surgical management of neuropathic pain is controversial and typical management of neuroma pain includes excision and transposition. In our institution, management includes a proximal crush injury to facilitate an axonal injury and a period of prolonged regeneration, neuroma resection with distal end cautery cap, and proximal intermuscular transposition. In the case, the patient presented with severe neuropathic pain in the anterior/lateral region of the ankle and foot, following surgery to correct flat foot deformity. Two attempts to surgically resolve the neuropathic pain from a sural neuroma failed before being referred to our institution. Examination and provocative tests revealed involvement of the sural nerve and superficial peroneal nerve. Surgical management included exploration and transposition of the sural nerve and superficial peroneal nerve with releases of the peroneal nerve at the fibular head, lateral sural nerve, and deep peroneal nerve. The nerves releases were included due to having positive provocative tests during examination. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804415761001_4791907192001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1986</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/anterior-interosseous-to-ulnar-motor-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/130912-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Anterior Interosseous to Ulnar Motor Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>Injury to the ulnar nerve results in clawing of the hand due to lost of ulnar intrinsic hand muscles, lost of ulnar-innervated wrist/finger flexion, and numbness/pain within the ulnar nerve territory of the hand. To prevent clawing and reconstruct the ulnar intrinsic hand muscles, the anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer is an available option. This involves transferring the distal pronator quadratus branch of the anterior interosseous nerve to the fascicular motor component of the ulnar nerve. This patient had an ulnar nerve injury following two ulnar nerve transpositions and reported pain and motor deficit immediately following surgery. He presented to our institution eight months post-injury and an end-to-end nerve transfer was elected due to the electrodiagnostic findings of fibrillations and no motor unit potentials by that time point. A Guyon's canal release, flexor digitorum profundus tenodesis for grip strength, and second revision ulnar nerve transposition was performed. This video includes details on the Guyon's canal release and anterior interosseous to ulnar motor end-to-end nerve transfer. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804429076001_4791860926001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>715</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/130912-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Anterior Interosseous to Ulnar Motor Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description> - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804441400001_4791858534001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1767</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-08</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/carpal-tunnel-release-persistent-symptoms-incomplete-release/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/131115-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Revision Carpal Tunnel Release in a Case of Persistent Symptoms and Incomplete Release - standard</video:title><video:description>Failure to resolve symptoms of carpal tunnel syndrome following a release of the flexor retinaculum can occur for a number of reasons. Failed carpal tunnel can be classified into three categories and include (1) persistent symptoms, (2) recurrent symptoms, and (3) new symptoms. Persistent symptoms of median nerve dysfunction can imply an incomplete release and/or wrong initial diagnosis with other associated problems, which can include proximal median nerve compression and/or cervical disc disease. Revision surgery is appropriate for patients with an incomplete release. In this case, the patient presented with a loss of median motor/sensory function immediately after surgery and pain in the territory of the palmar cutaneous branch of the median nerve. Provocative tests revealed findings comparable with an incomplete release of the carpal tunnel. Revision surgery was elected and an incomplete proximal release of the flexor retinaculum was found. Additionally, this patient had a palmar cutaneous branch with an aberrant course through the flexor retinaculum into the territory of the first incision. This branch was managed with a proximal transposition. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804468798001_4790670745001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>528</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/131115-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Revision Carpal Tunnel Release in a Case of Persistent Symptoms and Incomplete Release - extended</video:title><video:description>Failure to resolve symptoms of carpal tunnel syndrome following a release of the flexor retinaculum can occur for a number of reasons. Failed carpal tunnel can be classified into three categories and include (1) persistent symptoms, (2) recurrent symptoms, and (3) new symptoms. Persistent symptoms of median nerve dysfunction can imply an incomplete release and/or wrong initial diagnosis with other associated problems, which can include proximal median nerve compression and/or cervical disc disease. Revision surgery is appropriate for patients with an incomplete release. In this case, the patient presented with a loss of median motor/sensory function immediately after surgery and pain in the territory of the palmar cutaneous branch of the median nerve. Provocative tests revealed findings comparable with an incomplete release of the carpal tunnel. Revision surgery was elected and an incomplete proximal release of the flexor retinaculum was found. Additionally, this patient had a palmar cutaneous branch with an aberrant course through the flexor retinaculum into the territory of the first incision. This branch was managed with a proximal transposition. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804473942001_4790688878001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>992</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/revision-carpal-tunnel-release-proximal-median-nerve-hematoma/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120301-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Revision Carpal Tunnel Release in a Case of Proximal Median Nerve Hematoma Injury and Mild Compression - standard</video:title><video:description>Complications following carpal tunnel release are uncommon with patients experiencing persistent, recurrent, or new symptoms in the post-operative period. There are multiple etiologies for recurrent carpal tunnel syndrome, which can include traction neuropathy. This is when the epineurium of the median nerve adheres to the surrounding scar tissue and prevents normal nerve gliding leading to traction neuritis. This patient lost median nerve function due to a hematoma compression that developed from a peripherally inserted central catheter in the arm. While this patient did not have sensory function, he was recovering pronator teres and flexor carpi radialis function. For any possibility of sensory recovery, a revision carpal tunnel release was performed to ensure a complete release and mild compression of the median nerve was observed. The median motor function was augmented with a reverse end-to-side nerve transfer. This case is also a demonstration of bifid median nerve in the hand. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804467834001_4790518115001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>331</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120301-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Revision Carpal Tunnel Release in a Case of Proximal Median Nerve Hematoma Injury and Mild Compression - extended</video:title><video:description>Complications following carpal tunnel release are uncommon with patients experiencing persistent, recurrent, or new symptoms in the post-operative period. There are multiple etiologies for recurrent carpal tunnel syndrome, which can include traction neuropathy. This is when the epineurium of the median nerve adheres to the surrounding scar tissue and prevents normal nerve gliding leading to traction neuritis. This patient lost median nerve function due to a hematoma compression that developed from a peripherally inserted central catheter in the arm. While this patient did not have sensory function, he was recovering pronator teres and flexor carpi radialis function. For any possibility of sensory recovery, a revision carpal tunnel release was performed to ensure a complete release and mild compression of the median nerve was observed. The median motor function was augmented with a reverse end-to-side nerve transfer. This case is also a demonstration of bifid median nerve in the hand. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804473848001_4790518119001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>779</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/posterior-interosseous-nerve-release/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/130731-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Posterior Interosseous Nerve Release - standard</video:title><video:description>Compression of the posterior interosseous nerve can exhibit clinical weakness or functional loss of finger / thumb extension and lack of ulnar wrist extension. Provocative tests can confirm whether the radial tunnel in the region of the posterior interosseous nerve is the area of compression. Multiple anatomical structures can be involved in compressing the nerve in the tunnel, however the primary site of compression is the arcade of Froshe; this being the tendinous proximal border of the superficial head of the supinator. Other compressive structures can include the radial recurrent vessels (Leash of Henry) and tendinous proximal border of the extensor carpi radialis brevis. Decompression of the posterior interosseous nerve involves releasing these structures. If there is an associated lateral epicondylitis, release of the extensor carpi radialis brevis is taken further laterally. In this case, this patient presented with a recovering traumatic C7,8,T1 plexus injury. However, recovery of radial nerve function was halted for a few weeks with marked discomfort over the radial tunnel. Release of the posterior interosseous nerve was elected to promote more prompt and complete functional recovery. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804470783001_4788987874001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>404</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-06</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/130731-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Posterior Interosseous Nerve Release - extended</video:title><video:description>Compression of the posterior interosseous nerve can exhibit clinical weakness or functional loss of finger / thumb extension and lack of ulnar wrist extension. Provocative tests can confirm whether the radial tunnel in the region of the posterior interosseous nerve is the area of compression. Multiple anatomical structures can be involved in compressing the nerve in the tunnel, however the primary site of compression is the arcade of Froshe; this being the tendinous proximal border of the superficial head of the supinator. Other compressive structures can include the radial recurrent vessels (Leash of Henry) and tendinous proximal border of the extensor carpi radialis brevis. Decompression of the posterior interosseous nerve involves releasing these structures. If there is an associated lateral epicondylitis, release of the extensor carpi radialis brevis is taken further laterally. In this case, this patient presented with a recovering traumatic C7,8,T1 plexus injury. However, recovery of radial nerve function was halted for a few weeks with marked discomfort over the radial tunnel. Release of the posterior interosseous nerve was elected to promote more prompt and complete functional recovery. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804472257001_4788989026001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>955</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-06</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/transmuscular-ulnar-nerve-transposition-traumatic-medial-cord-injury/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/120405-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Transmuscular Ulnar Nerve Transposition in a Case of Traumatic Medial Cord Injury - standard</video:title><video:description>Cubital tunnel syndrome can present with pain/numbness in the ulnar nerve territory and weakness in the ulnar-innervated extrinsic/intrinsic muscles. The etiology for cubital tunnel syndrome depends on the case and includes various points of compression along the course of the ulnar nerve. The most common compression point is the medial epicondyle at which the fascial leading-edge of the flexor carpi ulnaris and the aponeurosis superficial to the cubital tunnel compress the nerve. However other compressive points can exist and can be under-recognized. The transmuscular ulnar nerve transposition (TUNT) addresses these compressive points by releasing and transposing the nerve through a transmuscular bed within the pronator-flexor muscle bundle. In this case, the patient had a traumatic medial cord injury and presented 1-year following with associated ulnar neuropathy and fibrillations/motor unit potentials. The TUNT was elected with a supercharge anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer, Guyon's canal release, and FDP tenodesis. This video highlights details of the TUNT. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804484598001_4772550288001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>607</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-24</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/120405-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Transmuscular Ulnar Nerve Transposition in a Case of Traumatic Medial Cord Injury - extended</video:title><video:description>Cubital tunnel syndrome can present with pain/numbness in the ulnar nerve territory and weakness in the ulnar-innervated extrinsic/intrinsic muscles. The etiology for cubital tunnel syndrome depends on the case and includes various points of compression along the course of the ulnar nerve. The most common compression point is the medial epicondyle at which the fascial leading-edge of the flexor carpi ulnaris and the aponeurosis superficial to the cubital tunnel compress the nerve. However other compressive points can exist and can be under-recognized. The transmuscular ulnar nerve transposition (TUNT) addresses these compressive points by releasing and transposing the nerve through a transmuscular bed within the pronator-flexor muscle bundle. In this case, the patient had a traumatic medial cord injury and presented 1-year following with associated ulnar neuropathy and fibrillations/motor unit potentials. The TUNT was elected with a supercharge anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer, Guyon's canal release, and FDP tenodesis. This video highlights details of the TUNT. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804490497001_4772488241001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1457</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-24</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/3rd-webspace-sensory-component-ulnar-nerve-transfer-pcm-dcu-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/130709-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>3rd Webspace to Sensory Component of Ulnar Nerve Transfer and PCM to DCU Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>Sensory nerve transfers are an available option for restoring sensation to critical deinnervated territories. Multiple strategies exist for restoring sensation, which include end-to-end nerve transfers for critical territories and end-to-side nerve transfers for non-critical territories. For sensory deficits in the ulnar nerve, the 3rd webspace fascicle from the median nerve can be utilized as a donor to reinnervate the ulnar territory of the hand, also known as the median to ulnar sensory nerve transfer. In this case, the patient suffered a traumatic ulnar nerve injury that was referred to our institution several years following for neuropathic pain. This was the patient's chief compliant and became the management priority. An ulnar nerve transection, proximal crush, cautery cap, and proximal transposition were elected. While this resolves the neuroma component of pain, there can still exist a hyperalgesia component, which distal nerve transfers would resolve through reinnervation. This video details the 3rd webspace to sensory component of the ulnar (end-to-end) nerve transfer. The distal 3rd webspace nerve was end-to-side transferred to the sensory component of the median nerve. Additionally, the palmar cutaneous branch of median nerve was (end-to-end) transferred to the dorsal cutaneous branch of ulnar nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804434678001_4789289382001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>758</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/130709-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>3rd Webspace to Sensory Component of Ulnar Nerve Transfer and PCM to DCU Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>Sensory nerve transfers are an available option for restoring sensation to critical deinnervated territories. Multiple strategies exist for restoring sensation, which include end-to-end nerve transfers for critical territories and end-to-side nerve transfers for non-critical territories. For sensory deficits in the ulnar nerve, the 3rd webspace fascicle from the median nerve can be utilized as a donor to reinnervate the ulnar territory of the hand, also known as the median to ulnar sensory nerve transfer. In this case, the patient suffered a traumatic ulnar nerve injury that was referred to our institution several years following for neuropathic pain. This was the patient's chief compliant and became the management priority. An ulnar nerve transection, proximal crush, cautery cap, and proximal transposition were elected. While this resolves the neuroma component of pain, there can still exist a hyperalgesia component, which distal nerve transfers would resolve through reinnervation. This video details the 3rd webspace to sensory component of the ulnar (end-to-end) nerve transfer. The distal 3rd webspace nerve was end-to-side transferred to the sensory component of the median nerve. Additionally, the palmar cutaneous branch of median nerve was (end-to-end) transferred to the dorsal cutaneous branch of ulnar nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804446011001_4789280984001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2212</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/nerve-entrapment-cme-update/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/130426-Thumbnail-Square-1.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Nerve Entrapment: CME Update</video:title><video:description>This presentation was given as a compliment to the CME article on nerve entrapment submitted to the Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery journal. Specifically, this presentation overviews the etiology, evaluation, and management of common compression neuropathies of the upper extremity. This includes a discussion on thoracic outlet syndrome, cubital tunnel syndrome, and carpal tunnel syndrome in additional to other compression neuropathies.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4864440646001_4864394176001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1331</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-04-26</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/median-nerve-release-in-the-forearm/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/120816-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median Nerve Release in the Forearm - standard</video:title><video:description>Compression neuropathy of the median nerve in the forearm, also known as pronator syndrome, typically presents with pain in the forearm +/- paresthesia/pain in the median nerve territory. The anterior interosseous nerve can be involved with a mononeuritis. While this usually resolves without surgery, occasionally will require this approach for reconstruction or release. Related anatomical structures include the lacertus fibrosus, deep head of pronator teres, arch of flexor digitorum superficialis, and fascia in the distal arm. Release of the median nerve in the forearm addresses these structures and decompresses the nerve in this area. This release is also a method for exposing the median nerve for reconstructive options. This patient presented with median nerve neuropathy in the forearm and hand. In addition to this forearm release, a carpal tunnel release was performed. This video portrays the median nerve decompression in the forearm. For acquiring adequate proximal exposure, a distal step-lengthening of the superficial head of pronator teres is performed. While surgical anatomy can differ from patient to patient, this patient had several tendinous fasciae as well as the deep head of pronator teres. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804469933001_4789964578001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>445</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/120816-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median Nerve Release in the Forearm - extended</video:title><video:description>Compression neuropathy of the median nerve in the forearm, also known as pronator syndrome, typically presents with pain in the forearm +/- paresthesia/pain in the median nerve territory. The anterior interosseous nerve can be involved with a mononeuritis. While this usually resolves without surgery, occasionally will require this approach for reconstruction or release. Related anatomical structures include the lacertus fibrosus, deep head of pronator teres, arch of flexor digitorum superficialis, and fascia in the distal arm. Release of the median nerve in the forearm addresses these structures and decompresses the nerve in this area. This release is also a method for exposing the median nerve for reconstructive options. This patient presented with median nerve neuropathy in the forearm and hand. In addition to this forearm release, a carpal tunnel release was performed. This video portrays the median nerve decompression in the forearm. For acquiring adequate proximal exposure, a distal step-lengthening of the superficial head of pronator teres is performed. While surgical anatomy can differ from patient to patient, this patient had several tendinous fasciae as well as the deep head of pronator teres. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804471511001_4789958498001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1027</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-07</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/carpal-tunnel-release/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/130320-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Carpal Tunnel Release - standard</video:title><video:description>Carpal tunnel syndrome is a compression neuropathy of the median nerve as it travels through the carpal tunnel deep to the transverse carpal ligament. This causes paresthesia and pain in the territory of the median nerve and weakness of the thenar muscles depending on the severity of the neuropathy. Paresthesia is most typically in the long/index finger as these nerve fascicles are located on the anterior aspect of the median nerve closest to the transverse carpal ligament. This patient presented with median nerve compression in the forearm and at the carpal tunnel release. A release was performed in the forearm. This video portrays the open carpal tunnel release. Principle points of this surgical technique include an incision ulnar to the thenar crease. This prevents injury to palmar cutaneous branch of the median nerve. In addition, division of the transverse carpal ligament ulnar to the median nerve prevents scarring directly over the nerve. While surgical anatomy can differ from patient to patient, this patient did not have a small palmar cutaneous nerve branching from the ulnar nerve, which can be encountered and easily protected through this incision. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804321309001_4774379389001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>344</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-25</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/130320-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Carpal Tunnel Release - extended</video:title><video:description>Carpal tunnel syndrome is a compression neuropathy of the median nerve as it travels through the carpal tunnel deep to the transverse carpal ligament. This causes paresthesia and pain in the territory of the median nerve and weakness of the thenar muscles depending on the severity of the neuropathy. Paresthesia is most typically in the long/index finger as these nerve fascicles are located on the anterior aspect of the median nerve closest to the transverse carpal ligament. This patient presented with median nerve compression in the forearm and at the carpal tunnel release. A release was performed in the forearm. This video portrays the open carpal tunnel release. Principle points of this surgical technique include an incision ulnar to the thenar crease. This prevents injury to palmar cutaneous branch of the median nerve. In addition, division of the transverse carpal ligament ulnar to the median nerve prevents scarring directly over the nerve. While surgical anatomy can differ from patient to patient, this patient did not have a small palmar cutaneous nerve branching from the ulnar nerve, which can be encountered and easily protected through this incision. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804332130001_4774358518001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>557</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-25</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/2014-crn-compression-neuropathies/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/140312-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2014 CRN – Compression Neuropathies</video:title><video:description>This presentation is part of the 2014 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures. Specifically, this presentation discusses compression neuropathies and includes topics of patient evaluation, thoracic outlet syndrome, ulnar nerve compression at the cubital tunnel and wrist, and median nerve compression in the forearm and wrist.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4873373913001_4873034329001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>5055</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-05-01</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/crn-brachial-plexus-lesions/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/120710-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2012 CRN &#8211; Brachial Plexus Lesions</video:title><video:description>This presentation was given for the 2012 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures. Specifically, this presentation discusses the topic of treatment for brachial plexus injuries, which includes presentation of common injury patterns, management algorithms for nerve injuries, pre-operative and post-operative therapy, and nerve transfers for shoulder and elbow function. Reconstructive options for common brachial plexus injuries are also discussed.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4870783147001_4870705383001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>5102</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-04-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/2012-crn-acute-nerve-injury-and-repair-part-2-nerve-transfers-in-the-hand/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/120502-2-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2012 CRN – Acute Nerve Injury and Repair Part 2: Nerve Transfers in the Hand</video:title><video:description>This presentation is the second part of the topic on Acute Nerve Injury and Repair given for the 2012 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures. Specifically, this presentation discusses reconstructive strategies for general topics in peripheral nerve surgery, which includes: nerve repair, nerve grafting, nerve allografts, conduits and acellularized nerve allografts, and nerve transfers. In respect to nerve transfers, the discussion is tailored towards end-to-side nerve transfers and what situation they are utilized for.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4870946506001_4870911276001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>3391</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-04-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/2012-crn-acute-nerve-injury-and-repair-peripheral-nerve-surgery/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/120502-1-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>2012 CRN – Acute Nerve Injury and Repair Part 1: Peripheral Nerve Surgery</video:title><video:description>This presentation is the first part of the topic on Acute Nerve Injury and Repair given for the 2012 Comprehensive Review of Neurosurgery video lectures. Specifically, this presentation discusses reconstructive strategies for general topics in peripheral nerve surgery, which includes: nerve repair, nerve grafting, nerve allografts, conduits and acellularized nerve allografts, and nerve transfers. In respect to nerve transfers, the discussion is tailored towards end-to-side nerve transfers and what situation they are utilized for.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4870943880001_4870878687001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>2315</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-04-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/transmuscular-ulnar-nerve-transposition/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/120410-Thumbnail-Square-Top-Align.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Transmuscular Ulnar Nerve Transposition</video:title><video:description>Transmuscular ulnar nerve transposition is our method for surgical management of cubital tunnel syndrome. Previously known as ”submuscular”, we have transitioned to ”transmuscular” as this term accurately describes this transposition as through the flexor muscles. This presentation describes the controversy surrounding different types of surgeries to manage cubital tunnel and we discuss our method with details including the physical examination, surgical management, and post-operative management. This presentation was presented during a 2012 Vumedi Webinar ”The Ulnar Nerve” and included other prominent panelists discussing their own individual experiences and techniques for management of cubital tunnel syndrome.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4862244037001_4862220221001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>612</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-04-25</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/anterior-interosseous-ulnar-motor-supercharge-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120404-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Anterior Interosseous to Ulnar Motor Supercharge Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>The supercharge nerve transfer is a procedure that coapts the distal end of a donor nerve to the side of the recipient nerve. Nerve regeneration is facilitated from donor to recipient through a perineurial window to enhance regeneration from the proximal regenerating nerve. This procedure can be used in cases of 2nd/3rd degree nerve injuries to augment motor recovery, with the advantages of a nerve transfer and without sacrificing the integrity and proximal regeneration of the recipient nerve. In this case, the patient had an iatrogenic medial cord injury. She presented 7 months following injury with ulnar intrinsic atrophy and fibrillations/motor unit potentials in her ulnar extrinsic/intrinsic muscles. The supercharge anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer was elected with a transmuscular ulnar nerve transposition, Guyon's canal release, and FDP tenodesis. This video highlights details of the supercharge nerve transfer, with specifics on the perineurial coaptation, Guyon's canal release, and FDP tenodesis. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804442076001_4783387083001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>552</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-02</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120404-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Anterior Interosseous to Ulnar Motor Supercharge Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>The supercharge nerve transfer is a procedure that coapts the distal end of a donor nerve to the side of the recipient nerve. Nerve regeneration is facilitated from donor to recipient through a perineurial window to enhance regeneration from the proximal regenerating nerve. This procedure can be used in cases of 2nd/3rd degree nerve injuries to augment motor recovery, with the advantages of a nerve transfer and without sacrificing the integrity and proximal regeneration of the recipient nerve. In this case, the patient had an iatrogenic medial cord injury. She presented 7 months following injury with ulnar intrinsic atrophy and fibrillations/motor unit potentials in her ulnar extrinsic/intrinsic muscles. The supercharge anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer was elected with a transmuscular ulnar nerve transposition, Guyon's canal release, and FDP tenodesis. This video highlights details of the supercharge nerve transfer, with specifics on the perineurial coaptation, Guyon's canal release, and FDP tenodesis. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804447056001_4783396564001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1349</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-02</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/median-to-radial-nerve-tendon-transfers-pt-to-ecrb-fcr-edc-pl-epl/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/111202-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median to Radial Nerve Tendon Transfers: PT to ECRB, FCR to EDC, PL to EPL - standard</video:title><video:description>Tendon transfers are an available option for reconstructing wrist and finger/thumb extension following radial nerve injury when nerve transfers are contra-indicated. The donor median-innervated tendons are used to reconstruct the recipient radial-innervated tendons. This tutorial describes the following tendon transfers: (1) pronator teres (PT) to extensor carpi radialis brevis (ECRB), (2) flexor carpi radialis (FCR) to extensor digitorum communis (EDC), and (3) palmaris longus (PL) to extensor pollicis longus (EPL). In this specific case, the patient had a left humeral fracture and lost complete radial nerve function. He consulted with our institution six months following the injury. While he was within the time limitation of nerve transfers, he elected for tendon transfers for radial nerve palsy. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804469002001_4786733540001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>757</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/111202-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median to Radial Nerve Tendon Transfers: PT to ECRB, FCR to EDC, PL to EPL - extended</video:title><video:description>Tendon transfers are an available option for reconstructing wrist and finger/thumb extension following radial nerve injury when nerve transfers are contra-indicated. The donor median-innervated tendons are used to reconstruct the recipient radial-innervated tendons. This tutorial describes the following tendon transfers: (1) pronator teres (PT) to extensor carpi radialis brevis (ECRB), (2) flexor carpi radialis (FCR) to extensor digitorum communis (EDC), and (3) palmaris longus (PL) to extensor pollicis longus (EPL). In this specific case, the patient had a left humeral fracture and lost complete radial nerve function. He consulted with our institution six months following the injury. While he was within the time limitation of nerve transfers, he elected for tendon transfers for radial nerve palsy. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804479996001_4786754019001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1749</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/median-fcrfds-radial-pinecrb-nerve-transfer-pronator-teres-ecrb-tendon-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/110711-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median (FCR/FDS) to Radial (PIN/ECRB) Nerve Transfer with Pronator Teres to ECRB Tendon Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>The median to radial nerve transfer is an available option for restoring radial nerve hand function following nerve injury. This nerve transfer specifically involves the transferring of two sets of nerves. That is, the flexor carpi radialis (FCR) to posterior interosseous nerve (PIN) and the flexor digitorum superficialis (FDS) to extensor carpi radialis brevis (ECRB) nerve transfers. This patient had a radial nerve palsy following a proximal humeral fracture. In conjunction to this nerve transfer in this case, the pronator teres to ECRB tendon transfer was also performed to reinforce and provide function to wrist extension through ECRB using pronator teres. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804390041001_4778897607001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>540</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/110711-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median (FCR/FDS) to Radial (PIN/ECRB) Nerve Transfer with Pronator Teres to ECRB Tendon Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>The median to radial nerve transfer is an available option for restoring radial nerve hand function following nerve injury. This nerve transfer specifically involves the transferring of two sets of nerves. That is, the flexor carpi radialis (FCR) to posterior interosseous nerve (PIN) and the flexor digitorum superficialis (FDS) to extensor carpi radialis brevis (ECRB) nerve transfers. This patient had a radial nerve palsy following a proximal humeral fracture. In conjunction to this nerve transfer in this case, the pronator teres to ECRB tendon transfer was also performed to reinforce and provide function to wrist extension through ECRB using pronator teres. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804398830001_4778917985001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1534</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/ganglion-cyst-removal-common-peroneal-nerve-fibular-head/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120213-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Ganglion Cyst Removal in the Common Peroneal Nerve at the Fibular Head - standard</video:title><video:description>There are various causes of common peroneal nerve palsy, however common peroneal nerve palsy caused by a ganglion cyst is uncommon. A benign tumor within the nerve sheath can cause compression and present with symptoms of neuropathy depending on the level of injury. In this specific case, the patient presented with a ganglion cyst in the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head. Typically, a ganglion cyst presents with a sudden onset of severe pain that is associated with a motor palsy. Magnetic resonance imaging revealed a cystic-appearing mass anterior to the fibular head, which was confirmed with a palpable mass. This resulted in compression neuropathy of the peroneal nerve. The surgical intervention included removal of the ganglion cyst and the decompression of the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804449794001_4786822508001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>425</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120213-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Ganglion Cyst Removal in the Common Peroneal Nerve at the Fibular Head - extended</video:title><video:description>There are various causes of common peroneal nerve palsy, however common peroneal nerve palsy caused by a ganglion cyst is uncommon. A benign tumor within the nerve sheath can cause compression and present with symptoms of neuropathy depending on the level of injury. In this specific case, the patient presented with a ganglion cyst in the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head. Typically, a ganglion cyst presents with a sudden onset of severe pain that is associated with a motor palsy. Magnetic resonance imaging revealed a cystic-appearing mass anterior to the fibular head, which was confirmed with a palpable mass. This resulted in compression neuropathy of the peroneal nerve. The surgical intervention included removal of the ganglion cyst and the decompression of the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804454716001_4786834135001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1004</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/pectoral-fascicle-middle-trunk-spinal-accessory-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120211-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Pectoral Fascicle of the Middle Trunk to Spinal Accessory Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>The pectoral fascicle of the middle trunk is an available donor nerve to transfer to restore spinal accessory nerve function. This procedure involves identifying the brachial plexus and the accessory nerve through a supraclavicular exposure. The pectoral fascicle is identified on the anterior aspect of the middle trunk deep to the identified upper trunk. Typically, two pectoral fascicles are identified and the fascicle that elicits a stronger contraction during electrical stimulation is utilized for transfer. The accessory nerve is identified along and deep to the anterior border of the trapezius. In this specific case, the patient had a proximal iatrogenic accessory nerve injury following a carotid endarterectomy four months prior to surgery, which precluded a direct repair of the accessory nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804470415001_4784728513001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>466</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-03</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/120211-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Pectoral Fascicle of the Middle Trunk to Spinal Accessory Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>The pectoral fascicle of the middle trunk is an available donor nerve to transfer to restore spinal accessory nerve function. This procedure involves identifying the brachial plexus and the accessory nerve through a supraclavicular exposure. The pectoral fascicle is identified on the anterior aspect of the middle trunk deep to the identified upper trunk. Typically, two pectoral fascicles are identified and the fascicle that elicits a stronger contraction during electrical stimulation is utilized for transfer. The accessory nerve is identified along and deep to the anterior border of the trapezius. In this specific case, the patient had a proximal iatrogenic accessory nerve injury following a carotid endarterectomy four months prior to surgery, which precluded a direct repair of the accessory nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804473149001_4784728517001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>976</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-03</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/tarsal-tunnel-release/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/110930-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Tarsal Tunnel Release - standard</video:title><video:description>Tarsal tunnel syndrome describes the compression of the tibial nerve through the tarsal tunnel which results in pain and numbness in the plantar aspect of the foot. The tibial nerve has three major branches which include the calcaneal, medial plantar, and lateral plantar nerve branches. There are two primary structures responsible for compression of the tibial nerve: (1) flexor retinaculum and (2) a septum that compartmentalizes the medial and lateral plantar nerves and the overlying fascia of the abductor hallucis muscle. The tarsal tunnel release involves releasing these structures. In this case, the patient had a traumatic injury to the lower leg, which required open reduction and internal fixation. The patient had pain and numbness in the tibial nerve distribution along with Tinel’s sign and positive scratch collapse at the tarsal tunnel. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804483600001_4779513006001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>493</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/110930-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Tarsal Tunnel Release - extended</video:title><video:description>Tarsal tunnel syndrome describes the compression of the tibial nerve through the tarsal tunnel which results in pain and numbness in the plantar aspect of the foot. The tibial nerve has three major branches which include the calcaneal, medial plantar, and lateral plantar nerve branches. There are two primary structures responsible for compression of the tibial nerve: (1) flexor retinaculum and (2) a septum that compartmentalizes the medial and lateral plantar nerves and the overlying fascia of the abductor hallucis muscle. The tarsal tunnel release involves releasing these structures. In this case, the patient had a traumatic injury to the lower leg, which required open reduction and internal fixation. The patient had pain and numbness in the tibial nerve distribution along with Tinel’s sign and positive scratch collapse at the tarsal tunnel. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804488915001_4779577985001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1052</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/superficial-peroneal-nerve-release-lower-leg/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/110921-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Peroneal Nerve Release in the Lower Leg - standard</video:title><video:description>Symptoms of a compressed superficial peroneal nerve in the lower leg includes numbness and tingling in the dorsal aspect of the foot and lateral aspect of the lower leg. These symptoms can be exaggerated when the peroneal nerve is under tension during movements of the leg and foot. Compression of the superficial peroneal nerve occurs due to the transverse crural ligament and the tight superficial fascia that encapsulates he lower leg musculature. The superficial peroneal nerve has a course just deep to this superficial fascia and exits superficially distal to the transverse crural ligament. Release of this fascia and ligament will decompress the superficial peroneal nerve. Other known areas of peroneal nerve compression include the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head and the deep peroneal nerve in the foot by the extensor hallucis brevis. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804482264001_4779601693001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>293</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/110921-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Superficial Peroneal Nerve Release in the Lower Leg - extended</video:title><video:description>Symptoms of a compressed superficial peroneal nerve in the lower leg includes numbness and tingling in the dorsal aspect of the foot and lateral aspect of the lower leg. These symptoms can be exaggerated when the peroneal nerve is under tension during movements of the leg and foot. Compression of the superficial peroneal nerve occurs due to the transverse crural ligament and the tight superficial fascia that encapsulates he lower leg musculature. The superficial peroneal nerve has a course just deep to this superficial fascia and exits superficially distal to the transverse crural ligament. Release of this fascia and ligament will decompress the superficial peroneal nerve. Other known areas of peroneal nerve compression include the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head and the deep peroneal nerve in the foot by the extensor hallucis brevis. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804484069001_4779545085001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>618</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/ulnar-index-median-ulnar-ring-ulnar-sensory-nerve-transfer-prevention-proximal-neuroma/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110817-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Ulnar Index of Median to Ulnar Ring of Ulnar Sensory Nerve Transfer and Prevention of Proximal Neuroma - standard</video:title><video:description>For distal sensory ulnar nerve injuries in the hand, there is an alternative approach in restoration of critical ulnar nerve sensation. In this case, the patient had a gunshot wound and required amputation of the small finger. As result, the ulnar aspect of the ring finger became the critical target for sensory reinnervation. In addition, soft tissue coverage of the palm was an obstacle for long nerve grafts. Goals were to restore critical sensation and prevent painful neuroma formation. The median nerve branch to the ulnar aspect of the index finger was used as the donor nerve to reinnervate the recipient ulnar nerve branch to the ulnar aspect of the ring finger. A nerve graft was required to bridge the distance and the ulnar sensory fascicle proximal to the injury was harvested as expendable graft material. An acellularized nerve allograft is used to extend the proximal end of the ulnar sensory fascicle for proximal transposition. To preserve rudimentary sensation to the donor nerve, an end-to-side nerve transfer to the lateral aspect of the long finger is completed. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804484605001_4784729892001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>622</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-03</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110817-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Ulnar Index of Median to Ulnar Ring of Ulnar Sensory Nerve Transfer and Prevention of Proximal Neuroma - extended</video:title><video:description>For distal sensory ulnar nerve injuries in the hand, there is an alternative approach in restoration of critical ulnar nerve sensation. In this case, the patient had a gunshot wound and required amputation of the small finger. As result, the ulnar aspect of the ring finger became the critical target for sensory reinnervation. In addition, soft tissue coverage of the palm was an obstacle for long nerve grafts. Goals were to restore critical sensation and prevent painful neuroma formation. The median nerve branch to the ulnar aspect of the index finger was used as the donor nerve to reinnervate the recipient ulnar nerve branch to the ulnar aspect of the ring finger. A nerve graft was required to bridge the distance and the ulnar sensory fascicle proximal to the injury was harvested as expendable graft material. An acellularized nerve allograft is used to extend the proximal end of the ulnar sensory fascicle for proximal transposition. To preserve rudimentary sensation to the donor nerve, an end-to-side nerve transfer to the lateral aspect of the long finger is completed. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804490023001_4784717474001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1437</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-03</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/common-peroneal-nerve-release-fibular-head/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110727-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Common Peroneal Nerve Release at the Fibular Head - standard</video:title><video:description>Compression of the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head is under recognized. Symptoms range from numbness and tingling in the posterior and lateral aspect of the lower leg and dorsal aspect of the foot to foot drop in severe cases of denervation. Symptoms can be exaggerated when the peroneal nerve is under tension during knee extension. The compression point of the common peroneal nerve is just distal to the fibular head as it dives deep to the peroneus longus. This is where the posterior crural intermuscular septum deep to the peroneus longus is found to be the primary contributing factor for the compression symptoms. Release of the common peroneal nerve involves dividing this intermuscular septum in addition to other tendinous septum planes and the tendinous fascia deep to the peroneal nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804436623001_4779364952001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>336</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110727-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Common Peroneal Nerve Release at the Fibular Head - extended</video:title><video:description>Compression of the common peroneal nerve at the fibular head is under recognized. Symptoms range from numbness and tingling in the posterior and lateral aspect of the lower leg and dorsal aspect of the foot to foot drop in severe cases of denervation. Symptoms can be exaggerated when the peroneal nerve is under tension during knee extension. The compression point of the common peroneal nerve is just distal to the fibular head as it dives deep to the peroneus longus. This is where the posterior crural intermuscular septum deep to the peroneus longus is found to be the primary contributing factor for the compression symptoms. Release of the common peroneal nerve involves dividing this intermuscular septum in addition to other tendinous septum planes and the tendinous fascia deep to the peroneal nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804441425001_4779342268001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>669</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/flexor-digitorum-profundus-tenodesis-median-fdp-ulnar-fdp/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/110617-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Flexor Digitorum Profundus Tenodesis (Median FDP to Ulnar FDP) - standard</video:title><video:description>For paralysis of ulnar-innervated flexor digitorum profundus (FDP) to the ring and small finger, tenodesis of the ulnar-innervated FDP tendons will allow the median-innervated FDP to drive the function of the ulnar-innervated FDP function. Specifically, the ulnar-innervated FDP tendons are sutured to the FDP tendon to the long finger, while the FDP tendon to the index finger is not included in this tenodesis. In this specific case, the patient had a complete ulnar nerve injury and the FDP tenodesis was performed in conjunction with the anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer, 3rd webspace to ulnar sensory nerve transfer, and Guyon's canal release. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804443246001_4778815190001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>245</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/110617-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Flexor Digitorum Profundus Tenodesis (Median FDP to Ulnar FDP) - extended</video:title><video:description>For paralysis of ulnar-innervated flexor digitorum profundus (FDP) to the ring and small finger, tenodesis of the ulnar-innervated FDP tendons will allow the median-innervated FDP to drive the function of the ulnar-innervated FDP function. Specifically, the ulnar-innervated FDP tendons are sutured to the FDP tendon to the long finger, while the FDP tendon to the index finger is not included in this tenodesis. In this specific case, the patient had a complete ulnar nerve injury and the FDP tenodesis was performed in conjunction with the anterior interosseous to ulnar motor nerve transfer, 3rd webspace to ulnar sensory nerve transfer, and Guyon's canal release. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804441343001_4778836491001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>364</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/thoracic-outlet-decompression/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110513-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Thoracic Outlet Decompression - standard</video:title><video:description>Neurological thoracic outlet 'inlet' syndrome (TOS) involves compression of the brachial plexus through the thoracic inlet. The neurologic symptoms of TOS can range from mild paresthesias and numbness in the upper extremity to intrinsic hand muscle atrophy. Thoracic outlet decompression entails decompressing the upper, middle, and lower trunks by dividing the anterior and middle scalene through a supraclavicular approach. Upon exposure, the platysma is divided and the supraclavicular nerves are protected. Upon approach, the omohyoid is divided. Prior to dividing the scalenes, the phrenic and long thoracic nerves are identified and protected. In this particular case, the platysma was scarce. A tourniquet is seen during orientation as an ulnar nerve transposition followed the thoracic outlet decompression in this patient. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804483761001_4778370013001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>581</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-28</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110513-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Thoracic Outlet Decompression - extended</video:title><video:description>Neurological thoracic outlet 'inlet' syndrome (TOS) involves compression of the brachial plexus through the thoracic inlet. The neurologic symptoms of TOS can range from mild paresthesias and numbness in the upper extremity to intrinsic hand muscle atrophy. Thoracic outlet decompression entails decompressing the upper, middle, and lower trunks by dividing the anterior and middle scalene through a supraclavicular approach. Upon exposure, the platysma is divided and the supraclavicular nerves are protected. Upon approach, the omohyoid is divided. Prior to dividing the scalenes, the phrenic and long thoracic nerves are identified and protected. In this particular case, the platysma was scarce. A tourniquet is seen during orientation as an ulnar nerve transposition followed the thoracic outlet decompression in this patient. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804490028001_4778318034001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1415</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-28</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/medial-triceps-branch-axillary-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110503-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Triceps Branch to Axillary Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>The medial triceps branch to axillary nerve transfer is an available option for reconstructing patients with shoulder deficits that include an axillary nerve injury. Not presented in this tutorial, the accessory to suprascapular nerve transfer is additionally performed to stabilize the humerus during its range-of-motion in these patients. The triceps to axillary nerve transfer specifically innervates the deltoid and teres minor. The superior lateral cutaneous branch of the axillary nerve is provided with rudimentary sensation through an end-to-side nerve transfer to the sensory component of the radial nerve. The surgical approach involves proceeding between the long and lateral head of the triceps brachii on the posterior aspect of the arm. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804454680001_4777491592001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>434</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-28</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110503-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Triceps Branch to Axillary Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>The medial triceps branch to axillary nerve transfer is an available option for reconstructing patients with shoulder deficits that include an axillary nerve injury. Not presented in this tutorial, the accessory to suprascapular nerve transfer is additionally performed to stabilize the humerus during its range-of-motion in these patients. The triceps to axillary nerve transfer specifically innervates the deltoid and teres minor. The superior lateral cutaneous branch of the axillary nerve is provided with rudimentary sensation through an end-to-side nerve transfer to the sensory component of the radial nerve. The surgical approach involves proceeding between the long and lateral head of the triceps brachii on the posterior aspect of the arm. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804463293001_4777521198001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1024</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-28</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/medial-antebrachial-cutaneous-nerve-graft-harvest/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110421-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Antebrachial Cutaneous Nerve Graft Harvest - standard</video:title><video:description>The medial antebrachial cutaneous (MABC) nerve is a viable donor for nerve grafts and our institution's preferred donor nerve graft for upper extremity nerve reconstructions. The MABC nerve is harvested from the medial aspect of the arm and is found branching distally into an anterior and posterior branch. The anterior and/or posterior branch can be harvested depending on the length and diameter required for nerve reconstruction. After harvesting the MABC nerve, the distal end of the MABC nerve is end-to-side transferred to an adjacent functional sensory nerve through an epineural window. in this case, the anterior branch of the MABC nerve is harvested for graft material and the anterior branch is end-to-side transferred to the posterior branch of the MABC nerve. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804451195001_4773232731001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>327</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-25</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/110421-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Medial Antebrachial Cutaneous Nerve Graft Harvest - extended</video:title><video:description>The medial antebrachial cutaneous (MABC) nerve is a viable donor for nerve grafts and our institution's preferred donor nerve graft for upper extremity nerve reconstructions. The MABC nerve is harvested from the medial aspect of the arm and is found branching distally into an anterior and posterior branch. The anterior and/or posterior branch can be harvested depending on the length and diameter required for nerve reconstruction. After harvesting the MABC nerve, the distal end of the MABC nerve is end-to-side transferred to an adjacent functional sensory nerve through an epineural window. in this case, the anterior branch of the MABC nerve is harvested for graft material and the anterior branch is end-to-side transferred to the posterior branch of the MABC nerve. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804453302001_4773172824001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>608</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-25</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/flexor-digitorum-superficialis-anterior-interosseous-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/110427-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Flexor Digitorum Superficialis to Anterior Interosseous Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>For isolated anterior interosseous nerve palsies, the nerve to the flexor digitorum superficialis (FDS) is an available donor to innervate the anterior interosseous nerve (AIN) for transfer. The FDS and AIN branch are found branching from the median nerve within the same upper-middle forearm region. The nerve to the FDS branches from the median nerve on its ulnar aspect while the AIN branches from the median nerve on its radial aspect. Prior to the nerve transfer, the median nerve is decompressed and exposed by step-lengthening the superficial head of pronator teres, releasing the deep head of pronator teres, and releasing the proximal tendinous arch of FDS. The FDS to AIN nerve transfer is an available option to restore AIN function. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804451151001_4777289003001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>345</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-27</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/110427-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Flexor Digitorum Superficialis to Anterior Interosseous Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>For isolated anterior interosseous nerve palsies, the nerve to the flexor digitorum superficialis (FDS) is an available donor to innervate the anterior interosseous nerve (AIN) for transfer. The FDS and AIN branch are found branching from the median nerve within the same upper-middle forearm region. The nerve to the FDS branches from the median nerve on its ulnar aspect while the AIN branches from the median nerve on its radial aspect. Prior to the nerve transfer, the median nerve is decompressed and exposed by step-lengthening the superficial head of pronator teres, releasing the deep head of pronator teres, and releasing the proximal tendinous arch of FDS. The FDS to AIN nerve transfer is an available option to restore AIN function. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804453441001_4777256103001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>859</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-27</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/tibial-nerve-decompression-soleus/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/110414-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Tibial Nerve Decompression at the Soleus - standard</video:title><video:description>Compression of the tibial nerve by the tendinous leading-edge of the soleus is rare but under recognized. The tibial nerve is decompressed by dividing the soleus arch found deep within the lower leg. The surgical approach involves proceeding between the lateral and medial gastrocnemius muscles. The soleus muscle is then identified deep to the gastrocnemius muscles, at which the tibial nerve is identified proximal to this muscle. The tibial nerve dives deep to the soleus arch, at which the compression point is found. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804482631001_4772968353001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>301</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-25</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/110414-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Tibial Nerve Decompression at the Soleus - extended</video:title><video:description>Compression of the tibial nerve by the tendinous leading-edge of the soleus is rare but under recognized. The tibial nerve is decompressed by dividing the soleus arch found deep within the lower leg. The surgical approach involves proceeding between the lateral and medial gastrocnemius muscles. The soleus muscle is then identified deep to the gastrocnemius muscles, at which the tibial nerve is identified proximal to this muscle. The tibial nerve dives deep to the soleus arch, at which the compression point is found. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804483238001_4772977282001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>509</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-25</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/thoracodorsal-long-thoracic-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/110328-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Thoracodorsal to Long Thoracic Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>Patients with long thoracic nerve injuries exhibit scapular winging and sever shoulder deficits that include the inability to forward flex the shoulder past 90 degrees of range of motion. Thoracodorsal to long thoracic nerve transfer utilizes a distal posterior branch of the thoracodorsal nerve to reinnervate the distal half of the long thoracic nerve. This operation occurs in the lateral aspect of the thorax. The distal half of the long thoracic nerve innervates the distal half of the serratus anterior, which inserts to the inferior angle of the scapula and provides scapular upward rotation during shoulder movements. A second procedure is used to reinnervate the proximal half of the serratus anterior. Together, the proximal and distal nerve transfers are known as the double-level nerve transfer for long thoracic nerve function. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804482810001_4785579381001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>304</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/110328-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Thoracodorsal to Long Thoracic Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>Patients with long thoracic nerve injuries exhibit scapular winging and sever shoulder deficits that include the inability to forward flex the shoulder past 90 degrees of range of motion. Thoracodorsal to long thoracic nerve transfer utilizes a distal posterior branch of the thoracodorsal nerve to reinnervate the distal half of the long thoracic nerve. This operation occurs in the lateral aspect of the thorax. The distal half of the long thoracic nerve innervates the distal half of the serratus anterior, which inserts to the inferior angle of the scapula and provides scapular upward rotation during shoulder movements. A second procedure is used to reinnervate the proximal half of the serratus anterior. Together, the proximal and distal nerve transfers are known as the double-level nerve transfer for long thoracic nerve function. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804485786001_4785564141001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>617</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/submuscular-ulnar-nerve-transposition/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/110307-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Submuscular Ulnar Nerve Transposition - standard</video:title><video:description>A submuscular ulnar nerve transposition is performed to decompress the ulnar nerve in the cubital tunnel at the elbow. The medial antebrachial cutaneous nerve is identified and protected. Proximally, the medial intermuscular septum is resected. A step-lengthening of the fascia of the flexor-pronator muscles is performed. The ulnar nerve is placed in a transmuscular location. More importantly, the distal fascial septum between the flexor carpi ulnaris and the flexor-pronator muscles is removed. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804482294001_4778801533001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>350</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/110307-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Submuscular Ulnar Nerve Transposition - extended</video:title><video:description>A submuscular ulnar nerve transposition is performed to decompress the ulnar nerve in the cubital tunnel at the elbow. The medial antebrachial cutaneous nerve is identified and protected. Proximally, the medial intermuscular septum is resected. A step-lengthening of the fascia of the flexor-pronator muscles is performed. The ulnar nerve is placed in a transmuscular location. More importantly, the distal fascial septum between the flexor carpi ulnaris and the flexor-pronator muscles is removed. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804489242001_4778823125001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1162</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-29</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/double-fascicular-transfer-median-fascicle-biceps-branch-ulnar-fascicle-brachialis-branch-nerve-transfers/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/101111-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Double Fascicular Transfer: Median Fascicle to Biceps Branch and Ulnar Fascicle to Brachialis Branch Nerve Transfers - standard</video:title><video:description>The double fascicular transfer (DFT) includes two nerve transfers: (1) median fascicle to biceps branch and (2) ulnar fascicle to brachialis branch. The median fascicle contains nerve fibers that innervate flexor digitorum superficialis / flexor carpi radialis. The ulnar fascicle contains nerve fibers that innervate flexor carpi ulnaris. The donor fascicles can be used for either recipient nerves depending on the length required, but the nerve transfers described above are typically used. The DFT is used to restore elbow flexion when median and ulnar nerves are intact. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804441338001_4785518831001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>422</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/101111-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Double Fascicular Transfer: Median Fascicle to Biceps Branch and Ulnar Fascicle to Brachialis Branch Nerve Transfers - extended</video:title><video:description>The double fascicular transfer (DFT) includes two nerve transfers: (1) median fascicle to biceps branch and (2) ulnar fascicle to brachialis branch. The median fascicle contains nerve fibers that innervate flexor digitorum superficialis / flexor carpi radialis. The ulnar fascicle contains nerve fibers that innervate flexor carpi ulnaris. The donor fascicles can be used for either recipient nerves depending on the length required, but the nerve transfers described above are typically used. The DFT is used to restore elbow flexion when median and ulnar nerves are intact. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804450775001_4785520217001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1289</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/anterior-interosseous-ulnar-motor-reverse-end-side-nerve-transfer/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/101020-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Anterior Interosseous to Ulnar Motor (Reverse End-to-side) Nerve Transfer - standard</video:title><video:description>The donor anterior interosseous nerve (AIN) is transferred to the side of the recipient ulnar motor fascicular group within the distal forearm to preserve ulnar nerve motor intrinsics. Guyon's canal release is a required part and is completed prior to this procedure. Specific to this case, a revision ulnar nerve transposition was completed proximally. This procedure is a variation of the end-to-end AIN to ulnar motor nerve transfer. The extended version includes both the Guyon's canal release and the reverse end-to-side nerve transfer. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804436168001_4786338191001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>332</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/101020-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Anterior Interosseous to Ulnar Motor (Reverse End-to-side) Nerve Transfer - extended</video:title><video:description>The donor anterior interosseous nerve (AIN) is transferred to the side of the recipient ulnar motor fascicular group within the distal forearm to preserve ulnar nerve motor intrinsics. Guyon's canal release is a required part and is completed prior to this procedure. Specific to this case, a revision ulnar nerve transposition was completed proximally. This procedure is a variation of the end-to-end AIN to ulnar motor nerve transfer. The extended version includes both the Guyon's canal release and the reverse end-to-side nerve transfer. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804443318001_4786338202001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>1130</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/carpal-tunnel-release-2/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/101025-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Carpal Tunnel Release</video:title><video:description>A carpal tunnel release is performed by decompressing the median nerve in the wrist through the carpal tunnel. This procedure involves transecting the transverse carpal ligament.</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804483228001_4785322865001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>424</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-03-04</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/median-nerve-forearm-decompression/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/101025-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median Nerve Forearm Decompression - standard</video:title><video:description>The median nerve is decompressed in the forearm. A Z-plasty lengthening is performed on the pronator teres tendon. In addition, the tendon of the deep head of the pronator teres is transected and the flexor digitorum superficialis tendinous arch is released. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804451207001_4778463954001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>314</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-28</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/101025-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Median Nerve Forearm Decompression - extended</video:title><video:description>The median nerve is decompressed in the forearm. A Z-plasty lengthening is performed on the pronator teres tendon. In addition, the tendon of the deep head of the pronator teres is transected and the flexor digitorum superficialis tendinous arch is released. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804453326001_4778370045001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>578</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-28</video:publication_date></video:video></url><url><loc>http://passioeducation.com/guyons-canal-release-carpal-tunnel-release/</loc><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/101025-1-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Guyon’s Canal Release and Carpal Tunnel Release - standard</video:title><video:description>The ulnar nerve is decompressed in the wrist through Guyon's canal and in the hand, specifically the deep motor branch of the ulnar nerve. This deep motor branch is released by dividing the tendious arch of the hypothenar muscles. In addition, a carpal tunnel release is performed by transecting the transverse carpal ligament. - standard</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804447064001_4772061435001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>320</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-24</video:publication_date></video:video><video:video><video:thumbnail_loc>http://passioeducation.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/101025-1-Thumbnail-Square.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc><video:title>Guyon’s Canal Release and Carpal Tunnel Release - extended</video:title><video:description>The ulnar nerve is decompressed in the wrist through Guyon's canal and in the hand, specifically the deep motor branch of the ulnar nerve. This deep motor branch is released by dividing the tendious arch of the hypothenar muscles. In addition, a carpal tunnel release is performed by transecting the transverse carpal ligament. - extended</video:description><video:content_loc>http://f1.media.brightcove.com/4/4741948344001/4741948344001_4804449732001_4774286109001.mp4</video:content_loc><video:duration>491</video:duration><video:publication_date>2016-02-25</video:publication_date></video:video></url></urlset>